1815 年拿破仑被除名
权力在岛上避难
1815 Napoleon, removed from
power took refuge on the island of
厄尔巴岛。虽然他的支持者
梦见他回来，
Elba. While his supporters
dream of his return,
新王权追求
他们无情地。期间
the new royal power pursues
them mercilessly. During the
内战，逮捕人数
和处决增加。
civil war, the number of arrests
and executions increases.
在海岸边的一个风雨交加的夜晚
科索角（科西嘉岛）的船
On a stormy night off the coast
of Cape Corso (Corsica), the ship
法老商人穿过小路
并发现了另一艘船的残骸......
Pharaoh merchant crosses the path
and finds wreckage of another ship...
你救了她。
You saved her.
递给我一条毯子！
Pass me a blanket!
我禁止他去那里！
I forbade him to go there!
到地下室去吧！我
直到马赛我才想见到你！
Go down to the basement! I
don't want to see you until Marseille!
什么？
What?
你觉得我残忍吗？
Do you think I'm brutal?
不仅我知道
那个，但我吹嘘它。
Not only do I know
that, but I brag about it.
我们走吧！
Let's go!
大家走吧
到你的帖子！
Let's go, everyone,
to your posts!
将其放在干燥的地方
在它被冻死之前。
Place it in a dry place
before it freezes to death.
等待！
Wait!
我们走吧！
Let's go!
拿破仑的消息
Napoleon's message
你睡的好吗？
Did you sleep well?
你有东西
那是属于我的。
You have something
that belongs to me.
我从未见过
皇帝的书写。
I had never seen
the Emperor's writing.
把这封信还给我。
Give me this letter back.
我不这么认为，不。
I don't think so, no.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
一个不举报她的好理由。
A good reason not to report her.
尝试银色。
Try silver.
它经常起作用。
It often works.
我没有。
I don't have any.
但我有朋友。
But I have friends.
如果你正在说话
关于这封信，
If you are talking
about this letter,
他们会找到你
他们会杀了你，
they will find you
and they will kill you,
腾格拉尔船长。
Captain Danglars.
先生？
Sir?
我给你带来了很多麻烦。
I caused you a lot of trouble.
我不知道该如何感谢你。
I don't know how to thank you.
刚刚做了这个。
Just did this.
小心。
Take care.
错过...？
Miss...?
安琪儿.
Angele.
埃德蒙.
Edmond.
我永远不会忘记
你的勇气。
I will never forget
your courage.
但忘了我的名字。
But forget my name.
再见，埃德蒙。
Goodbye, Edmond.
再见，安杰尔。
Goodbye, Angele.
莫雷尔想见他。
Morrel wants to see him.
我们刚刚换班，
科索角海岸附近。
We had just changed shift,
off the coast of Cape Corso.
海浪很大。我们
距离沉船200噚。
The waves were strong. We
were 200 fathoms from the wreck.
把日志给我。
Give me the logbook.
我们正陷入废墟时，唐太斯
想划着小船离开
We were hitting the rubble when Dantès
wanted to leave with the rowing boat
我禁止了它。太疯狂了。
I banned it. It was crazy.
- 那么真相呢？
- 是的，先生。
- And truth?
- Yes sir.
- 我们会为我们的一个人做这件事。
- 这是我的决定。
- We would have done it for one of our men.
- It was my decision.
- 我承担了我的责任。
- 我订购了
- I assumed my responsibilities.
- I ordered
我们必须转向
周围，​​他潜水了。
we would have to turn
around and he dived.
你潜水了吗？
Did you dive?
船长有
不禁止潜水。
The captain had
not prohibited diving.
这就够了。
That's enough.
你见过这种无礼的行为吗？
Have you seen this insolence?
莫雷尔先生，我告诉你，
这个男孩已经失控了。
Mr Morrel, I tell you,
this boy is out of control.
我不想扬帆
不再和他在一起了。
I don't want to sail
with him anymore.
- 你不会再和他一起航行了。
- 我警告过你。
- You won't sail with him anymore.
- I warned you.
- 因为你不会
不再为我扬帆。
- Because you won't
sail for me anymore.
饶恕？
Forgiveness?
- 你怎么能让她淹死？
- How could you let her drown?
- 我...救了你
货物，莫雷尔勋爵。
- I... saved your
cargo, Lord Morrel.
- 唐太斯得救了
尊敬的腾格拉尔。
- Dantes saved
my honor, Danglars.
腾格拉尔船长，你
不再是队长了。
Captain Danglars, you
are no longer captain.
快去收拾你的东西吧。
Go pack your things.
- 我会支付你的余额。
- 我们不知道这个女人是谁。
- I will pay your balance.
- We don't know who this woman is.
我知道你做了什么。
这对我来说就足够了。
I know what you did.
And that's enough for me.
男孩，过来。
Boy, come here.
我们走吧！
Let's go!
让这成为你的一个教训。
Let this be a lesson for you.
啊？
Huh?
当你是个男人的时候，我们
不要躲在我们的立场背后
When you're a man, we
don't hide behind our position
甚至不在桌子下面。
not even under a table.
我向你呈现
I present to you
我的孙子，马克西米连。
my grandson, Maximilien.
很高兴，马克西米连。
Delighted, Maximilien.
马克西米连，我介绍
给你唐泰斯船长。
Maximilien, I present
to you Captain Dantes.
早上好，队长。
Good morning, captain.
那么几岁了...
So how old...
队长？
Captain?
- 是的，尝试展示自己
值得，埃德蒙。
- Yes, try to show yourself
worthy of it, Edmond.
当然，先生。
Of course, sir.
当然。
Of course.
啊？
Huh?
那很好。
That is good.
她鼓舞人心。埃德蒙！
She inspires. Edmond!
我简直不敢相信。
I can't believe it.
我必须...我已经
告诉你一些事情。
I have to... I have
to tell you something.
谁爱我？
Who loves me?
是的...那个。但...
Yes... that. But...
- 不，没有“但是”。
- 等待。
- No, there are no “buts”.
- Wait.
- 但我...
- 重新开始。
- But I...
- Start again.
你亲吻了未来的队长。
You kiss a future captain.
- 你会...
- 是的。
- You will be...
- Yes.
- 那么我们可以...
- 是的。我们一定能做到。
- Then we can...
- Yes. We will be able to.
我很想念你。
I missed you.
我很想念你。我很想念你。
I missed you. I missed you.
稍后见。
See you later.
埃德蒙！
Edmond!
-朱丽叶。 你还好吗？
- 你呢？
-Juliette. Are you well?
- And you?
是的。
Yes.
- 你好吗？
- 这是埃德蒙，路易斯的儿子。
- How are you?
- It's Edmond, Louis' son.
- 你好先生。
- 早上好。
- Hello sir.
- Good morning.
- 爸爸在哪儿？ 我必须见他。
- 在家里。
- Where is daddy? I have to see him.
- At home.
稍后见。
See you later.
你可以微笑，
You can smile,
这是个好消息。
this is good news.
你扮鬼脸。
You grimace.
这是喜悦。
It's joy.
我为你感到骄傲。
I'm so proud of you.
队长。
Captain.
已通知先生及
德·马尔塞夫夫人？
Notified Mr. and
Mrs. de Morcerf?
还没有。我想要
先告诉你。
Not yet. I wanted
to tell you first.
一切都在进行
改变吧，爸爸。
Everything is going
to change, dad.
你必须告诉他们。
You have to tell them.
——这都是他们的功劳。
- 你也是。
- It's all thanks to them.
- And you too.
我没有付钱
你的海军研究。
I didn't pay for
your naval studies.
来吧，我的儿子。
Come on, my son.
去瞻仰一下吧。
Go and pay your respects.
所以，干杯！我举起酒杯
So, cheers! I raise my glass
为了纪念他的母亲埃德蒙。
in memory of his mother, Edmond.
因为我们想念她
Because we miss her
并且因为她生下了
and because she gave birth
马赛最年轻队长！
Marseille's youngest captain!
- 太棒了！
- 为他鼓掌，他会不舒服。
- Bravo!
- Applaud him, he will be uncomfortable.
在那里，完美。
There, perfect.
但最重要的是
But most of all
因为玛蒂尔德·唐太斯
because Mathilde Dantès
她是的保姆
未来的法国夫妇
She was the nanny of
a future French couple
走向英雄的命运，
to a heroic destiny,
最好的之一
欧洲官员，
one of the best
officers in Europe,
打电话给费尔南德
马尔塞夫，为您服务。
Call Fernand
Morcerf, to serve you.
路易斯，过来干杯吧
我们。这就是机会。
Louis, come and toast with
us. This is the opportunity.
谢谢您，先生。
Thank you, sir.
稍后，也许吧。
Later, perhaps.
你可以斥责梅赛德斯。
她不再听我说话了。
You can reprimand Mercédès.
She doesn't listen to me anymore.
也许她会是
婚礼迟到了。
Maybe she'll be
late for the wedding.
- 啊，终于！
- 哦。
- Ah, finally!
- Oh.
抱歉我的延误，
Sorry for my delay,
我的阿姨。你好叔叔。
my aunt. Hello uncle.
贺拉斯·德·巴利奥斯
Horace de Balios
做了他想做的事。
我差点撞到他了。
did what he wanted.
I almost hit him.
但无论如何，梅赛德斯。
But anyway, Mercédès.
这位先生是谁？
Who is this gentleman?
这是一匹马。他来了
来自一个非常好的家庭。
It's a horse. He comes
from a very good family.
- 早上好，我的表弟。
- Good morning, my cousin.
埃德蒙.
Edmond.
梅赛德斯。
Mercédès.
你准备好了吗
派对？埃德蒙有大消息。
Are you ready for the
party? Edmond has big news.
是的，是的。
Yes yes.
是的，我将成为队长。
Yes, I will be captain.
法老的
队长。这是官方的。
Pharaoh's
Captain. It's official.
- 那么真相呢？
- 唔。
- And truth?
- Hmm.
- 好工作。
- 为了队长！
- Good job.
- For the captain!
- 我有！
-哦！ 为了您的健康！
- I have!
-Oh! For your health!
- 我为你感到高兴。
- 我也是。 我很高兴
- I'm happy for you.
- Me too. I am happy
- 为我。 健康。
- 你打算买一套新制服吗？
- for me. Health.
- Are you going to buy a new uniform?
还有新的工资。
And a new salary.
他就能享受生活，
He will be able to enjoy life,
利用
的好天气。
to take advantage
of the good weather.
我们会向您解释。
We will explain it to you.
我将能够得到
结婚了，最重要的是。
I will be able to get
married, above all.
什么？
What?
你将成为我的见证人。
You will be my witness.
- 别指望它！
- 嗯，是的！
- Don't count on it!
- Well, yes!
浪费的见证！
梅塞德斯，说句话。
The witness of a waste!
Mercédès, say something.
- 我试过了，但他疯狂地爱着。
- 哦，完全疯了。
- I tried, but he's madly in love.
- Oh, completely crazy.
她知道这一点吗？
最后，她同意吗？
And does she know this?
Finally, does she agree?
是的。从她告诉我的情况来看，
Yes. From what she told me,
- 是的，是的。
- 我知道。
- Yes yes.
- I know.
是朱丽叶。
It's Juliet.
- WHO？
- 有着顽皮脸的女裁缝。
- Who?
- The seamstress with the naughty face.
不！不，这不是朱丽叶。
No! No, it's not Juliette.
不，这是一个真正的女人，
No, it's a real woman,
很漂亮。
very beautiful.
不仅仅是漂亮。
Not just pretty.
唔。
Hmm.
- 神秘而迷人。
- 是的！ 不不，
- Mysterious and captivating.
- Yes! No no,
- 是的，是的。
- 但是谁？
- Yes yes.
- But who is it?
她是你的表弟。
She is your cousin.
梅塞德斯·埃雷拉·德·马尔塞夫。
Mercédès Herrera de Morcerf.
你？
You?
- 是的。
- 我们结婚吧。
- Yes.
- Let's get married.
但她完全疯了。
But she's completely crazy.
还有你妈妈
永远不会想要。
And your mother
will never want to.
- 你认为妈妈
可以拒绝我什么吗？
- Do you think mom
can refuse me anything?
然后你就会说服她。她
一直是你最喜欢的侄女。
Then you will convince her. She
was always your favorite niece.
阿们！
AMEN!
我把它带到这里，
I carry it here,
由维尔福先生签署，
signed by Mr. de Villefort,
国王的律师，
King's Attorney,
逮捕令
这个人名叫爱德蒙·唐太斯。
an arrest warrant for the
man named Edmond Dantès.
- 跟着我们。
- Follow us.
这是怎么回事？
What's going on?
- 不，留下它。
- 必须有一个解释。
- No, leave it.
- There must be an explanation.
- 来。
- 让我走。
- Come.
- Let me go.
- 等待。
- 费尔南德，做点什么！
- Wait.
- Fernand, do something!
- 这是什么？我的儿子
没有做任何事情。
- What is it? My son
didn't do anything.
这一定是一个误会。
This must be a misunderstanding.
他们要去哪里
他？我会陪你。
Where are they taking
him? I will accompany you.
- 我们必须单独对付他，先生。
- 中尉。
- We must take him alone, sir.
- Lieutenant.
费尔南·德·马尔塞夫中尉。
Lieutenant Fernand de Morcerf.
告诉你的朋友
让我们过去。
Tell your friends
to let us pass.
这是真正的订单。
It's a real order.
我会处理的。
I'll take care of it.
- 现在请关注我们。
-埃德蒙！
- Please follow us now.
-Edmond!
我会回来的，我的爱人。
I will be back, my love.
埃德蒙·唐泰斯，律师先生。
Edmond Dantès, Mr. Attorney.
离开我们。
Leave us.
我一直很欣赏
像你这样的水手，唐太斯先生。
I've always admired
sailors like you, Mr. Dantès.
我只是害怕大海。
I'm just afraid of the sea.
确实如此，这无尽的深渊。
It's true, this endless abyss.
这些黑水。
These black waters.
怪物似乎总是做好准备
出来吞噬你。
A monster always seems ready
to come out and devour you.
- 我被指控什么？为什么
我会在婚礼上被捕吗？
- What am I being accused of? Why
am I being arrested at my wedding?
你有吗
敌人，唐泰斯大人？
Do you have any
enemies, Lord Dantes?
一个……敌人？
A... an enemy?
或者嫉妒。
Or jealous.
刚刚被任命为​​队长，你是
会嫁给一个美丽的伴侣...
Just been named captain, You're
going to marry a beautiful match...
它可能使
人们嫉妒。
It might have made
people jealous.
我不知道，不。
I don't know, no.
我有不同意见
最近和船员一起，
I had a disagreement
recently with a crew member,
但他能指责我什么呢？
But what could he accuse me of?
我不知道。
I don't know.
成为一个拿破仑
例如，代理。
To be a Napoleonic
agent, for example.
饶恕？
Forgiveness?
但是……这没有意义。
But... that doesn't make sense.
- 我们发现了这个
圣经在你的小屋里。
- We found this
Bible in your cabin.
这是你的圣经吗？
Is this your Bible?
上面写着你的名字。
It has your name written on it.
是的，最后，是这样的
仍然不构成犯罪。
Yes, finally, it is
still not a crime.
和真相。
And truth.
但我们也发现了一个
里面的任务指令
But we also found a
mission order inside
拿破仑亲笔签名。
signed in Napoleon's own hand.
这是犯罪行为。
And that is a crime.
等待。
Wait.
不，这是第一次
我看过这封信。
No, this is the first time
I have seen this letter.
如果没有敌人，谁会
可以把它放在那里吗？
If there is no enemy, who
could have put it there?
在科索角海岸附近，我
救了一名溺水的年轻女孩。
Off the coast of Cape Corso, I
saved a young girl from drowning.
她在你的小屋里向你道谢了吗？
Did she thank you in your cabin?
不。
No.
腾格拉尔锁住了她
那里。她离开了马赛。
Danglars locked her
there. She left in Marseilles.
你可以检查一下。
You can check.
询问工头
加斯帕·卡德鲁斯。
Ask the foreman
Gaspar Caderousse.
- 卡德鲁斯？
- 是的。
- Caderousse?
- Yes.
你对她了解多少？
What do you know about her?
没有什么。
Nothing.
唐泰斯先生。
Mr Dantes.
我采访了几十个
阴谋者的
I interviewed dozens
of conspirators
我不认为
这是其中之一。
and I don't think
it's one of them.
我想帮助一个
马尔塞夫家族的朋友，
I would like to help a
friend of the Morcerfs,
但我需要你帮助我。
but I need you to help me.
我发誓我不知道
关于她的任何事情。
I swear I don't know
anything about her.
她告诉我她的名字叫安吉拉。
She told me her name was Angèle.
就这样。
That's all.
你...
You...
你有暴露这个年轻吗
女人的名字给任何人吗？
Did you reveal this young
woman's name to anyone?
不。
No.
连这个卡德鲁斯也不行吗？
Not even for this Caderousse?
不。
No.
不为任何人。荣誉的话。
For no one. word of honor.
你看，唐太斯先生，
我相信你。
You see, Mr. Dantès,
I believe in you.
然而我还是会被逼
为了让它保持更长的时间，
However, I will be forced
to keep it a little longer,
提问时间
其余的船员。
time to question
the rest of the crew.
如果他们证实了你的证词
对此我毫不怀疑，
If they confirm your testimony,
of which I have no doubt,
我会把你还给你的新娘
你会有很多时间来恨我。
I will return you to your bride, that
you will have a lot of time to hate me.
指望她。
Count on her.
费尔南德将带来
它返回给你。
Fernand will bring
it back to you.
我受不了
再说了，我走了。
I can't take it
anymore, I'm going.
我无能为力了。
There's nothing more I can do.
这对你有好处
如果他们不释放他。
It would be good for you
if they didn't release him.
怎么能说出如此恐怖的话呢？
How can you say such horrors?
热拉尔，无论他们说什么
关于唐太斯，我保证。
Gérard, whatever they told
you about Dantès, I guarantee it.
先生们，请稍等一下。
Leave us a moment, gentlemen.
费尔南德 我真是这样
对你的朋友感到抱歉。
Fernand, I'm so
sorry about your friend.
我知道你们的关系。
I know your connections.
但他并不知道一切。
But he doesn't know everything.
我们找到了任务指令
从皇帝身上传到他身上。
We found a mission order
from the Emperor on him.
而他的同伴们则说
他是他们的支持者之一。
And his companions say
he is one of their supporters.
我想你明白
这些指控的严重性。
I think you understand the
seriousness of these accusations.
此前他曾被捕
与梅塞德斯结婚
He was arrested before
marrying Mercédès
并且无法挽回的
没有承诺，
and that the irreparable
is not committed,
但如果你愿意担保
but if you're willing to vouch,
如果你认为这些
两个男人都在说谎……
If you think these
two men are lying...
如果你愿意的话
冒这个风险，
If you are willing
to take that risk,
那我就放你自由。
then I will set you free.
你只有一个字要说。
You only have one word to say.
不。
No.
不？
No?
他不值得...
He doesn't deserve it...
他不值得什么？
What doesn't he deserve?
愿我们一家人
名字会被玷污。
May our family
name be tarnished.
如果唐太斯背叛了我们
If Dantes betrayed us,
愿他受苦吗
叛徒的命运。
may he suffer
the fate of traitors.
我可以确定...
I can be sure...
愿没有诉讼玷污
马尔塞夫家族的声誉。
May no lawsuit tarnish the
reputation of the Morcerfs.
我需要你的证词。
I'll need your testimony.
你明白吗
怎么了？
Do you understand
what is happening?
所以闭嘴。
So shut up.
- 唐太斯先生？
- 你能和检察官谈话吗？
- Mr. Dantès?
- Were you able to speak to the prosecutor?
- 是的，先生。
- Yes sir.
这是我不会忘记的一天。
This is a day I will not forget.
你不带我回家吗？
Won't you take me home?
不，事实上。
No, in fact.
我们走吧。
Let's go.
怎么了？
What is happening?
让我走吧。
Let me go.
打电话给检察官我
与检察官交谈！
Call the Prosecutor I
spoke to the Prosecutor!
和他谈谈。跟他说话！
Talk to him. Talk to him!
我是无辜的！我没有
做任何事！让我走吧。
I'm innocent! I didn't
do anything! Let me go.
嘘，嘘，嘘。
Shh, shh, shh.
你就会有罪，你
会被绞死的。我们带你，
You would have been guilty, you
would have been hanged. We take you,
因为他知道事情
我们不想听。
because he knows things
we don't want to hear.
我们走吧。
Let's go.
停止。
Stop.
停止！
Stop!
让我走吧！
Let me go!
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
我什么也做不了。
I couldn't do anything.
梅赛德斯。
Mercédès.
离开我吧。
Leave me.
这不会有任何好处。
It wouldn't do any good.
-梅赛德斯...
- 停下来。
-Mercédès...
- To stop.
请。
Please.
怎么了，维多利亚？
What's wrong, Victoria?
- 见到我你不高兴吗？
- 你姐姐在这里。
- Aren't you happy to see me?
- Your sister is here.
维尔福小姐。
Miss de Villefort.
《秘密》非常适合你。
Clandestine suits you perfectly.
抱歉我无法返回
的赞美。
Sorry I can't return
the compliment.
白兰地？对不起，
我的海水没了
Brandy? Sorry,
I'm out of sea water.
是的，这是我的工作
知道一切。
Yes, it's my job to
know everything.
所以你知道
唐太斯是无辜的。
So you know that
Dantes is innocent.
无辜...是的。
Innocent... Yes.
谁是真正无辜的？
Who is really innocent?
他什么也没做。
你为什么阻止他？
He didn't do anything.
Why did you stop him?
但为了救你的命。
But to save your life.
我的生命还是你的名声？
My life or your reputation?
- 我们都从事政治。
- We are both in politics.
在政治上，我们做
不排除一个男人，
In politics, we do
not exclude a man,
我们已经消除了一个障碍。
we have removed an obstacle.
我就知道他练过
他的职业残酷，
I knew that he practiced
his profession with cruelty,
但我期待你
诚实地去做。
but I expected you
to do it honestly.
你为什么不
代替他举报？
Why don't you
report it in his place?
但我会的，热拉尔。
But I will, Gérard.
如果你拒绝
救救他，我会的。
If you refuse to
save him, I will.
但你愿意
人们忽视我的存在
But would you rather
people ignore my existence,
维多利亚的，
Victoria's,
你的爱人，
Your lover,
和你未来的孩子。
and your future child.
这正是我的想法。
That's exactly what I thought.
活？
Alive?
活。
Alive.
活？
Alive?
活！
Alive!
活？
Alive?
活。
Alive.
走远点...
离开海岸...
Go far away...
Leave the coast...
谁知道
方式...谁知道具体...
And who knows the
way... Who knows exactly...
有人在吗？
Is anyone there?
有人。
There is someone.
有人在吗？
Is anyone there?
有人。
There is someone.
- 你是谁？
- Who are you?
呃，我……唐泰斯，爱德蒙·唐泰斯。
Uh, I... Dantès, Edmond Dantès.
- 你今年多大？
- How old are you?
- 你的声音听起来像个年轻人。
- 我有...
- Your voice sounds like a young man.
- I have...
我不知道了。
I don't know anymore.
那年我22岁...
当他们把我锁起来的时候。
I was 22 years old...
when they locked me up.
1815 年 5 月 16 日。
May 16, 1815.
那是四年前的事了。
It was four years ago.
他今年 26 岁。
He is 26 years old.
四年？
Four years?
和...
AND...
而你，你是谁？
And you, who are you?
一个囚犯。
A prisoner.
就像你一样。
Like you.
已经多久了？
How long has it been?
嘘！
Shh!
什么？
What?
- 他们来了。
- 等待。
- They're coming.
- Wait.
别离开我。
Don't leave me.
你是谁？在
至少告诉我你的名字。
Who are you? At
least tell me your name.
你的名字！
Your name!
诈骗
Scams
34！活？
34! Alive?
活。
Alive.
我在等你。
I was waiting for you.
你真的认为
你能离开这里吗？
Do you really think
you can get out of here?
六年里我挖了30m。
I dug 30 m in six years.
绕过您的手机
并到达外面，
To bypass your cell
and reach the outside,
你必须
挖两倍的时间。
you will have to
dig twice as long.
12年？
12 years?
现在可能会少一点
我们将有两个人。
Maybe a little less, now
that there will be two of us.
为了什么？你
还有其他计划吗？
For what? Do you
have other plans?
不。
No.
我是方丈法利亚。
I am Abbot Faria.
爱德蒙·唐泰斯.
Edmond Dantes.
你没见过这封信吗？
Have you never seen this letter?
不，从来没有。
No, never.
你呢？你
知道你为什么在这里吗？
And you? Do you
know why you're here?
- 是的。
- Yes.
他们想让你闭嘴。
我，他们想让我说话。
They wanted to silence you.
Me, they wanted to make me talk.
我选择我信任的人。
I choose people I trust.
不懂意大利语？
Don't know Italian?
- 不。
- 英语、阿拉伯语、拉丁语、希腊语？
- No.
- English, Arabic, Latin, Greek?
我只知道大海。
I only know the sea.
如果你愿意，我就教你。
If you want, I'll teach you.
带着耐心和渴望，...
With patience and desire,...
6、7年后，你会
知道我所知道的一切。
in 6 or 7 years, You will
know everything I know.
历史、哲学、
History, philosophy,
数学。
mathematics.
这些都是...
These are...
这些是武器
These are weapons
就是这样的解放。
that are as liberating as this.
唔。
Hmm.
第一件事是什么
你要做的
What's the first thing
you're going to do
我们可以离开吗？
if we can leave?
我要去寻找梅赛德斯。
I'm going to find Mercédès.
如果你会怎么做
她没有等你吗？
What would you do if
she didn't wait for you?
所以我不会有
不再有任何事了。
So I won't have
anything anymore.
我要告诉你
一个故事，埃德蒙。
I'm going to tell you
a story, Edmond.
他鼓舞人心。
He inspires.
700年前，
700 years ago,
在耶路撒冷期间，
第一次十字军东征，
in Jerusalem, during
the first crusade,
骑士们
the knights
负责保护基督的坟墓，
他们创建了圣殿骑士团。
responsible for protecting Christ's tomb,
they created the order of the Templars.
第一天，
On the first day,
他们只有几个，
但他们有巨大的信念。
there are only a few of them,
but they have immense faith.
感谢你们的胜利，
Thanks to your victories,
秩序
积累财富...
the Order
accumulates a fortune...
大量。
considerable.
康西……相当大。
Consi... Considerable.
我告诉你最伟大的宝藏
地球曾经承载过的。
I tell you about the greatest treasure
that the Earth has ever carried.
和...
AND...
随着时间的推移，
over time,
他的权力，他的财富，
让人嫉妒。
his power, his wealth,
make people jealous.
1307 年 10 月 13 日星期五，
法国国王，美男子菲利普，
And on Friday, October 13th, 1307,
the king of France, Philip the Fair,
下令逮捕他
orders his arrest
并没收他们的资产。
and seizure of their assets.
但从来没有人
找到了宝藏。
But no one ever
found the treasure.
他知道...
He knows...
这些骑士做了什么
拥有如此巨大的财富？
What did these knights do
with this immense fortune?
- 不。
- 没有什么！
- No.
- Nothing!
埃德蒙，没什么。
Edmond, nothing.
忙着报仇，
Too busy getting revenge,
来惩罚那些
谁背叛了他们，
to punish those
who betrayed them,
他们相继死去。
they died one after the other.
嗯，几乎所有人。
Well, almost everyone.
他们中的最后一个
The last of them
这是红衣主教斯帕达。
it was Cardinal Spada.
在他生命的最后时刻，
基督山岛上的避难所，
At the end of his life, taking
refuge on the island of Monte Cristo,
他有时间
训练最后一名骑士。
he had time to
train one last knight.
这个年轻人名叫……
This young man was called...
朱塞佩·法利亚.
Giuseppe Faria.
我是最后的幸存者，埃德蒙。
I am the last survivor, Edmond.
他鼓舞人心。我知道
He inspires. And I know
宝藏在哪里。
where is the treasure.
一半
Half of that
今天又回到你身边。
comes back to you today.
但你会怎样
这笔财富怎么办？
But what will you
do with this fortune?
会有好处的
It will do good
或者你会让你的
心中充满仇恨？
or will you let your
heart fill with hate?
我要去清空袋子。
I'm going to empty the bag.
埃德蒙.
Edmond.
啊？
Huh?
她是咸的。
She's salty.
水是咸的。
The water is salty.
我们快到了。
这是几天的事。
We're almost there.
It's a matter of days.
我们在那里，我们在那里。
We are there, we are there.
我会回来的。
I will be back.
远离！
Stay away!
方丈？
Abbot?
方丈？方丈？
Abbot? Abbot?
他呻吟着。
He groaned.
然后。
Then.
-埃德蒙。
- 不，不，别说话。
-Edmond.
- No, no, don't talk.
我会寻求帮助。
I'll ask for help.
不。
No.
太晚了。
It's too late.
别伤心。
Don't be sad.
你曾是唯一
是我生命中的安慰。
You have been the only
consolation in my life.
主给了我...
The Lord gave me...
有点晚了，但是
他把它给了我。
a little late, but
he gave it to me.
我没有疯，埃德蒙。他哭了。
I'm not crazy, Edmond. He cries.
我知道。
I know.
宝藏是存在的。
The treasure exists.
你知道在哪里可以找到它。
You know where to find it.
我们一起去吧！
Let's go together!
别忘了。
Don't forget.
基督山。
Monte Cristo.
山...
Mount...
方丈？
Abbot?
住持。
Abbot.
方丈？
The abbot?
别离开我。
Don't leave me.
别离开我。呃？
Don't leave me. Eh?
别离开我。
Don't leave me.
活？
Alive?
活！
Alive!
活？
Alive?
17 号？
Number 17?
哦，17岁！
Oh, 17!
方丈？
Abbot?
哦，阿博特？
Oh, Abbot?
哦！他死了，扔掉袋子！
Oh! He's dead, throw the bag!
努力的呻吟
Moans of effort
它是什么？
What it is?
住持。
The abbot.
活？
Alive?
活！
Alive!
活？
Alive?
常设。
Standing.
常设！
Standing!
我说起来吧！
I said get up!
警报！
Alert!
一...
ONE...
警报！
Alert!
二...
TWO...
警报！
Alert!
还有三个！
AND THREE!
嘿！这里没什么可做的。
Hey! There's nothing to do here.
离开！
Go away!
我是来看看
路易斯.路易斯·唐泰斯.
I came to see
Louis. Louis Dantes.
你认识路易斯吗？
Did you know Louis?
是的。
Yes.
我们埋葬了他，可怜的路易斯。
We buried him, poor Louis.
很久以前了。
A long time ago.
不，这是不可能的。
No, it's not possible.
他死于饥饿
当他的儿子去世时。
He died of hunger
when his son died.
他想加入他。
He wanted to join him.
但他的...
But his...
但你的儿子并没有死。
But your son is not dead.
对不起。
Sorry.
你也是一名水手吗？
Were you also a sailor?
- 是的。
- 唔。
- Yes.
- Hmm.
我给你吃点东西。
但随后它就消失了，对吗？
I'll give you something to eat.
But then it disappears, right?
还有梅塞……梅塞德斯？
And Mercé... Mercédès?
费尔南·德·马尔塞夫呢？
And Fernand de Morcerf?
- 一定是7或8
距离他们上次来已经有很多年了。
- It must have been 7 or 8
years since they last came.
他们曾在巴黎生活过
自从他们的儿子出生以来。
They have lived in Paris
since the birth of their son.
已经很晚了。
It's very late.
避开利古里亚海
Avoid the Ligurian Sea
以及他们不间断的巡逻。
and their incessant patrols.
前往撒丁岛。
Head to Sardinia.
你可以停在圣诞老人那里
特蕾莎·迪·加卢拉。
You can stop in Santa
Teresa di Gallura.
蒙特岛
基督位于
The island of Monte
Christ is located
托斯卡纳群岛以西。
west of the Tuscan Archipelago.
它将降落在遥远的南方。
It will land in the far south.
我知道你会印象深刻
以其朴素之美。
I know you will be impressed
by its austere beauty.
我羡慕他发现
这是第一次。
I envy him discovering
this for the first time.
然后。
Then.
它就在那里。
It's there.
的金库
显赫的斯帕达家族。
The vault of the
illustrious Spada family.
剩下的，埃德蒙，
The rest, Edmond,
这是你的故事。
It's your story.
一个拥有世界的男人
That of a man who has the world
在你的手掌中。
in the palm of your hand.
马赛 一年后
Marseille One year later
- 请继续。
- 停止。
- Please go ahead.
- Stop.
- 我明天付钱给你。
- 不不。 加斯帕，出去。
- I'll pay you tomorrow.
- No no. Gaspar, get out.
卡德鲁斯先生
是我的一个朋友。
Mr. Caderousse
is a friend of mine.
埃德蒙临终前
唐太斯要我分享
On his deathbed, Edmond
Dantes asked me to share
在那些人之中
对他来说很重要。
among those who
were important to him.
他以为他已经
受到腾格拉尔某位人士的谴责。
He thought he had been
denounced by a certain Danglars.
但他坚信两个
人们仍然忠于他。
But he was convinced that two
men had remained loyal to him.
他告诉我：
He told me:
“有一个叫
加斯帕德·卡德鲁斯,
“One is called
Gaspard Caderousse,
“第二个，
费尔南·德·马尔塞夫。”
"and the second,
Fernand de Morcerf."
保留你的钻石。
Keep your diamond.
我们谁都不配得到任何东西。
None of us deserve anything.
等等，我的儿子。
Wait, my son.
如果我向你透露我所知道的事情
我们会知道它来自我。
If I reveal to you what I know,
we will know it came from me.
还有这些人
有钱有势。
And these people
are rich and powerful.
没什么好害怕的
There's nothing to fear,
我受以下约束
坦白的秘密。
I am bound by the
secrecy of confession.
坐下。
Sit down.
唐太斯对腾格拉尔的看法是正确的。
他就是举报他的人。
Dantes was right about Danglars.
He was the one who reported him.
但是费尔南·德·马尔塞夫呢？
他是你的朋友。
But Fernand de Morcerf?
He was your friend.
你能和
你垂涎谁的妻子？
Can you be friends with the
one whose wife you covet?
出于对梅赛德斯的热爱，
For the love of Mercédès,
他牺牲了爱德蒙。
he sacrificed Edmond.
他会活下去。但对于
所有人，他都会死。
He will live. But for
everyone, he will be dead.
唔。
Hmm.
唯一一个愿意
值得唐太斯喜爱的是莫雷尔。
The only one who would
deserve Dantès' affection is Morrel.
船主？
The ship owner?
他为他而战
被释放。
He fought for him
to be released.
他也是，普罗维登斯
很少感谢他。
And he too, Providence
thanked him very little.
唐太斯被捕后，
After Dantes' arrest,
不得不接受腾格拉尔
回来担任队长。
had to accept Danglars
back as captain.
但腾格拉尔也背叛了他。
But Danglars also betrayed him.
摧毁了他一半的舰队
Destroyed half of his fleet,
据称是被海盗偷走的。
allegedly stolen by pirates.
莫雷尔毁了
出售公司。
Ruined, Morrel had
to sell the company.
猜猜是谁
花点微薄的钱买的？
And guess who
bought it for a pittance?
腾格拉尔。
Danglars.
两个月后，
船又出现了。
Two months later,
the boats reappeared.
但检察官
维尔福没有屈服。
But the Prosecutor
Villefort did not give in.
必须要说的是
他们分享了一个秘密。
It must be said that
they shared a secret.
小维多利亚，
维尔福的情人，
Little Victoria,
Villefort's lover,
成为腾格拉尔夫人。
became Madame Danglars.
今天她是男爵夫人。
She is a baroness today.
莫雷尔死于贫困。
Morrel died in poverty.
而你呢，在
卡德鲁斯先生，这一切？
And what about you, in
all this, Mr. Caderousse?
你？
You?
我能做什么
What could I do
面对队长，
伯爵和检察官？
facing a captain, a
count and a procurator?
如果我再勇敢一些，我可能
就会像她一样结束。
If I had been braver, I probably
would have ended up like her.
她？
She?
安琪儿.
Angele.
她去看她了
哥哥去救唐太斯。
She had gone to see her
brother to save Dantès.
我释放了自己
I freed myself
唐太斯着。起来了
让你摆脱它。
by Dantes. It's up
to you to get rid of it.
看？我也有朋友。
Look? I also have friends.
发生了什么？
What happened?
她被杀了吗？
Was she killed?
她的痛苦就会少一些。
She would have suffered less.
腾格拉尔有
为她制定其他计划。
Danglars had
other plans for her.
他把它卖给了美拉德兄弟，
土伦的篮筐大师。
He sold it to the Maillard brothers,
the basket masters of Toulon.
小的本来就很漂亮
The little one was beautiful,
得到了一个很好的价格。
got a good price for it.
他什么都知道
但什么也没做。
He knew everything
and did nothing.
我很惭愧，父亲。
I'm ashamed, Father.
总有一天我会回来。
One day I will return.
我将为您提供
救赎自己的机会。
And I will offer you the
opportunity to redeem yourself.
我不再来祈祷
为你或寻找你，
I no longer come to pray
for you or look for you,
但只是想让你知道：
but just to let you know:
我会做你做不到的事。
I will do what you couldn't do.
从今以后，我就是那个人了
谁奖励谁惩罚。
From now on, I'm the one
who rewards and punishes.
你想要什么吗？
Do you want something?
- 你是谁？
- Who are you?
几年前，
Years ago,
你告诉我：
you told me:
“我不会忘记你的
勇气，但忘了我的名字。”
"I will not forget your
courage, but forget my name."
还好我没有忘记
你的名字或你的勇气。
Well, I haven't forgotten
your name or your courage.
唐太斯。
Dantes.
我是来接你的，安吉拉。
I came to get you, Angèle.
对我来说，已经太晚了。
For me, it's too late.
但它可以拯救孩子。
But it can save the child.
孩子？
The child?
当我到达这里时，
When I arrived here,
我脑子里只有一个想法：
I only had one idea in mind:
为我的兄弟报仇。
take revenge on my brother.
几个星期以来，我一直在寻找
寻找逃跑的方法。
For weeks, I searched
for a way to escape.
有一天，机会来了
自我呈现。我逃跑了。
One day, the opportunity
presented itself. I ran away.
和一个客户。
With a client.
来自巴黎的木匠。
A carpenter from Paris.
我知道杰拉德
被任命在那里。
I knew that Gérard had
been appointed there.
我找到了维多利亚的踪迹
I found Victoria's trail,
你的爱人。
your lover.
我想继续
故事从哪里结束。
I wanted to continue
the story where it left off.
天气很冷。
It was very cold.
那天晚上...
That night...
杰拉德必须死。
Gérard would have to die.
没有什么可以阻止我。
Nothing could stop me.
我仍然能感觉到金属
我手里的刀。
I can still feel the metal
of the knife in my hand.
但一切都没有按计划进行。
But nothing went as planned.
维多利亚在哭。
Victoria's crying.
当杰拉尔走进去时
花园里，他提着一个箱子。
When Gérard went out into the
garden, he was carrying a trunk.
我跟着他。
I followed him.
当我靠近的时候……婴儿哭了
I got closer when... baby crying
当我听到
孩子低沉的哭声。
When I heard the
muffled cry of a child.
我不能离开她。
I couldn't leave her.
他还有他母亲的
他体内的血液。
He still had his mother's
blood in his body.
在复仇与生命之间……
Between revenge and life...
我选择了生活。
I chose life.
我和他一起逃跑了。
I ran away with him.
我在巴黎一个人也不认识。
I didn't know anyone in Paris.
然后我就回到了我的商店。
Then I went back to my store.
但兄弟俩
美拉德找到了他。
But the brothers
Maillard found him.
他们正在等我。
And they were waiting for me.
安吉丽...
Angele...
孩子怎么了？
What happened to the child?
你好安德烈。
Hello André.
安吉尔让我来接你。
Angèle made me come get you.
为了什么？
For what?
她会死的。
She will die.
我会带你去见她
她可以说再见了。
I'll take you to her so
she can say goodbye.
然后我们就离开。
Then we will leave.
让我们采取...
Let's take...
所有的时间都需要做好准备。
all the time needed to be ready.
准备好做什么？
Ready to do what?
为了报仇，安德烈。
To get revenge, André.
报复
三个男人偷走了他的生命
Take revenge on the
three men who stole his life,
你的
yours
和我的。
and mine.
- 我想杀了他们。
- 那会很容易。
- I want to kill them.
- That would be very easy.
非常甜蜜。
Very sweet.
不。
No.
我们必须挖出他们的心。
We have to rip out their hearts.
- 你是谁？
- Who are you?
- 我是伯爵
基督山。
- I am the Count
of Monte Cristo.
五年后的巴黎
Paris Five years later
马尔塞夫将军决定
今天放弃军队
General de Morcerf decided
today to abandon the army
将一生奉献给政治，
在贵族院里。
to dedicate his life to politics,
in the Chamber of Peers.
法国军队
失去了一位伟大的战士，
The French army
loses a great soldier,
但法国却多了一位伟人。
but France gains a great man.
费尔南·德·马尔塞夫
Fernand de Morcerf
战斗在莫斯科，战斗在莱比锡，
fought in Moscow, in Leipzig,
在土耳其...
in Türkiye...
无处不在，危险重重
他一生捍卫
Everywhere, at the risk
of his life, he defended
的某个想法
法兰西王国。
a certain idea of ​​the
kingdom of France.
费尔南德付出了代价
肉体的承诺和尊重
Fernand paid the price of his
commitment and respect in the flesh
给定单词的。
of the given word.
10年前，
而法国的盟友
10 years ago,
while France's ally
阿里·帕克萨·德·贾尼娜 (Ali Paxá de Janina)
被土耳其军队包围，
Ali Paxá de Janina was
surrounded by Turkish troops,
马尔塞夫上校
扔掉了所有东西。
Colonel de Morcerf
threw everything.
在一个
勇敢的士兵的中队，
At the head of a
squadron of brave soldiers,
取得突破
奥斯曼帝国的背后
achieved a breakthrough
behind the Ottomans
来给你的
盟友伸出援助之手。
to come and give your
ally a helping hand.
这疯狂的勇气之举
This act of insane courage
不幸的是，它不会是
够了，但所有法国人都知道：
unfortunately it will not have been
enough, but all the French know it:
“我们不打仗
成功的希望！
“We do not fight in
the hope of success!
“不！不，还有更多
没用的时候也很美丽。”
"No! No, it's much more
beautiful when it's useless."
是不是更好了？
Is it better?
他不是很专心
致尤金妮·腾格拉尔。
He wasn't very attentive
to Eugénie Danglars.
- 父亲。
- 她将有200万嫁妆，
- Father.
- She will have 2 million dowry,
婚礼当天。
on the wedding day.
费尔南多！
Fernand!
所以我必须付钱
注意他的财富。
So I must pay
attention to his fortune.
最好减去一个
奖章并加一个零。
Better minus a
medal and plus a zero.
我们的儿子是他那个时代的人。
他是一个浪漫主义者，相信...
Our son is a man of his time.
He's a romantic who believes in...
归还奖牌！
Return the medal!
那里！
There!
这就够了。
That's enough.
如果我知道你的荣幸
访问，我会做好准备的。
If I had known the honor of your
visit, I would have prepared for it.
如果我知道你的荣幸
访问，我会做好准备的。
If I had known the honor of your
visit, I would have prepared for it.
外部！
Outside!
先生们...如果我有的话
知道您的光临，
Gentlemen... If I had
known the honor of your visit,
我会为此做好准备的。
I would have prepared for that.
很抱歉收到
你在一个临时家里。
I'm sorry to receive
you in a makeshift home.
我去过法国
很短一段时间。
I've been in France
for a short time.
算了，我惭愧了
来打扰你,
Count, I'm ashamed
to bother you,
但我们永远不能
谢谢你够了。
but we can never
thank you enough.
我确信他会
为我做了同样的事。
I'm sure he would have
done the same for me.
算了，我欠你一条命。
Count, I owe you my life.
我很高兴见到你
重新站起来。
I'm glad to see you
back on your feet.
我下令维修
已经裂开的十字架。
I ordered repairs to
the cross that had split.
现在它是你的了。
It's yours now.
非常感谢，
但我不能接受。
Thank you very much,
but I can't accept it.
我已经欠你一笔债了
我不知道如何付款。
I already owe you a debt
that I don't know how to pay.
你喜欢武器吗？
Do you like weapons?
请。
Please.
这是我最
美丽的作品。
It's one of my most
beautiful pieces.
奥斯曼风格手枪。
Ottoman style pistol.
是的，但是铁卫
刻有树叶
Yes, but the iron guard
engraved with foliage
表明这个桶是
欧洲制造。
indicates that this barrel is
of European manufacture.
实际上来自威尼斯。
From Venice, actually.
你是一位鉴赏家。
You are a connoisseur.
我的父亲战斗过
对抗苏丹库尔西
My father fought
against Sultan Khursit
与阿里·帕克萨并肩作战。
alongside Ali Paxá.
马尔塞夫.
Morcerf.
难道是著名的
马尔塞夫将军？
Is it the famous
general from Morcerf?
我印象非常深刻。
I'm very impressed.
你愿意尝试吗？
Would you be willing to try?
不幸的是，我是
预计在会议厅举行。
Unfortunately, I am
expected in the Chamber.
- 下次。
- 只需要一会儿。
- Next time.
- It'll only take a moment.
你值得你的声誉，
You deserve your reputation,
一般来说。
in general.
让我们改变一下
目标是你，阿尔伯特。
Let's change the
target to you, Albert.
提醒我永远不要挑战你
Remind me never to challenge you
为了决斗。
for a duel.
感谢您留下您的
儿子陪我几个小时。
Thank you for leaving your
son with me for a few hours.
我迫不及待地想了解更多关于这个的信息
上帝已经安排了我的道路。
I can't wait to learn more about the one
that providence has placed in my path.
我要参加男爵
周日腾格拉尔的狩猎。
I will participate in Baron
Danglars' hunt on Sunday.
加入我们。
Join us.
我不能，我必须
欢迎卡瓦尔坎蒂王子的儿子。
I won't be able to, I have to
welcome Prince Cavalcanti's son.
来吧，我们俩。
会有足够的鹿。
Come on, both of us.
There will be enough deer.
再见。
See you soon.
我希望直到周日。
Until Sunday, I hope.
一切都好吗？
Everything is fine?
我保留了一个小金属纪念品
远离我的奥斯曼住宿。
I kept a small metal souvenir
away from my Ottoman stay.
更喜欢唱
带枪的歌？
Prefer to sing the
song with guns?
跟我来。
Follow me.
请原谅我。
Please forgive me.
我无意
不尊重……你的妻子。
I had no intention of
disrespecting... your wife.
海黛不是我的妻子。
她是我的干女儿。
Haydée is not my wife.
She is my goddaughter.
您先请。
After you.
海迪。
Haydee.
多么美妙的名字啊。
What a wonderful name.
这是一个很常见的
希腊的名字。
It is a very common
name in Greece.
它可以翻译为...
谦虚或……纯真。
It could be translated as...
modesty or... innocence.
我可以请你吗
把我介绍给海黛？
May I ask you to
introduce me to Haydée?
他看起来像一个
值得信赖的年轻人。
He seems like a
trustworthy young man.
此外，我还要向您介绍
海黛，但你必须向我保证。
Furthermore, I will introduce you to
Haydée, but you must make me a promise.
我会这样做
你提前。
I will do this for
you in advance.
我不是在开玩笑。
I'm not kidding.
永远不要试图引诱她。
Never try to seduce her.
所以你认为我很危险？
So you think I'm dangerous?
不。
No.
但她是。
But she is.
如果你不遵守诺言
她会伤你的心
If you don't keep your promise,
she will break your heart
和他的。
and his.
- 但...
- 她还没准备好去爱。
- But...
- She's not ready to love yet.
你声音的秘密
可以在你的过去找到。
The secret to your voice
can be found in your past.
父亲被杀后，
她被卖给了瓦拉几部落。
After her father's murder,
she was sold to a Vlach tribe.
那是我遇见的地方
并欢迎她。
That's where I met
and welcomed her.
你知道，有
悲伤和心痛
You know, there are
sorrows and heartaches
需要数年时间才能治愈。
that take years to heal.
他们在灵魂上留下一层面纱。
They leave a veil over souls.
切勿尝试举起
这面纱，阿尔伯特。
Never try to lift
this veil, Albert.
我保证。
I promise.
好的。
Good.
你会轻柔地行走，
看也不看我们一眼。
You will walk softly,
without a glance at us.
你只会转身
当我打电话给你的时候。
You're only going to turn
around when I call you.
海迪。
Haydee.
阿尔贝托·德·马尔塞夫
向您介绍海黛。
Alberto de Morcerf, I
present to you Haydée.
高兴极了。
Delighted.
着迷了。
Enchanted.
很高兴认识你，小姐。
Nice to meet you, miss.
如果他不这样做怎么办
想认识我吗？
What if he doesn't
want to meet me?
他会的。
He will.
起来！
Stand up!
站起来就是生存。
To stand is to survive.
隐藏我们成长的地方
贫穷，是为了生存。
Hide that we grew up in
poverty, it's about surviving.
你明白吗？为什么，安德烈？
Do you understand? Why, André?
因为我是王子
安德烈亚·卡瓦尔坎蒂
Because I am Prince
Andreia Cavalcanti.
- Cavalcanti，这不是山羊的意思吗？
- 什么？
- Cavalcanti, doesn't that mean goat?
- What?
不要感到惊讶。
听我说“什么”？
Don't be surprised.
Hear me say "what"?
恢复。
Resume.
我是王子
安德里亚·卡瓦尔坎蒂
I am the prince
Andrea Cavalcanti.
- 你没有口音
王子。这是怎么做到的？
- You don't have an accent,
prince. How is this done?
非常严格的老师
让我用棍子把它弄丢了。
A very strict teacher
made me lose it with a stick.
傲慢无礼。你的肘部。
Insolence. Your elbows.
亲爱的伯爵，
Dear Count,
- 很高兴认识你。
- 请允许我告诉你一个秘密。
- Pleasure to meet you.
- Allow me a secret.
法国人的生活仍是未知数
对我来说，请原谅我
French life is still unknown
to me, please excuse me
如果我的举止显得太斯拉夫式，
那不勒斯语或阿拉伯语给你。
if my manners seem too Slavic,
Neapolitan or Arabic to you.
这是基督山伯爵
和安德烈·卡瓦尔坎蒂王子。
This is the Count of Monte Cristo
and Prince Andrea Cavalcanti.
- 先生们。
- 数数。
- Sirs.
- Count.
王子。
Prince.
见到你父亲，不
无论多么令人不安，
Meeting your father, no
matter how disturbing it is,
不应该分散你的注意力
你的目标：腾格拉尔男爵。
should not distract you from
your target: Baron Danglars.
多亏了被盗的船只，
在奴隶制中发了财。
Thanks to the stolen boats,
made a fortune in slavery.
- 你的声誉先于你。
- 不要被他的笑容所迷惑。
- Your reputation precedes you.
- Don't be fooled by his smile.
他很残酷。他不仅
知道这一点，但为此感到自豪。
He is brutal. He not only
knows this, but is proud of it.
我可以向你表白吗？
Can I make you a confession?
法国人的生活仍然未知
我，我会请求你原谅我
French life is still unknown to
me, I will ask you to forgive me
如果我的举止显得太斯拉夫式，
那不勒斯语或阿拉伯语给你。
if my manners seem too Slavic,
Neapolitan or Arabic to you.
当你有钱的时候，你可以
任何事情都不要做得太多。
When you are rich, you can
never be too much at anything.
你的女儿是
你的弱点。
Your daughter is
your weak point.
王子。
Prince.
男爵。
Baron.
- 尤金妮.
- 地形好不好？
- Eugénie.
- Is the terrain good?
- 太完美了。
- 那我们走吧。
- It's perfect.
- Then let's go.
先生们，骑马吧。
On horseback, gentlemen.
伯爵阁下。
Your Honor, Count.
非常感谢，
Thank you very much,
但我很久以前就做过了
but I did it a long time ago
誓杀正义
为自己辩护。
the oath to kill just
to defend myself.
那么让我来为你辩护吧。
So let me come to your defense.
完美的。
Perfect.
王子。
Prince.
不客气。
You're welcome.
我们吃午饭吧。
Let's have lunch.
尤金妮？
Eugénie?
- 谢谢。苏珊娜，我介绍
安德烈·卡瓦尔坎蒂王子，
- Thanks. Suzanne, I present
to you Prince Andrea Cavalcanti,
意大利门徒
基督山。
the Italian protégé
of Monte Cristo.
他照顾我。
He takes care of me.
我爸爸怕美女
巴黎让我做蠢事。
My father is afraid that the beauties
of Paris make me do stupid things.
法语说得很完美。
Speaks French perfectly.
一位非常严格的老师
我用棍子失去了我的口音。
A very strict teacher made
me lose my accent with sticks.
- 但这太可怕了。
- 最重要的是，这是假的。
- But it's horrible.
- It's false, above all.
- 我的母亲是法国人。
- 真是个白痴。
- My mother is French.
- What an idiot.
很高兴你能加入我们。
Glad you could join us.
他的门徒的手
没有颤抖。
His protégé's hand
did not tremble.
动物甚至没有受苦。
The animal didn't even suffer.
这是一个执行
专家与您对话。
And this is an execution
expert talking to you.
你经常撞头吗？
Do you often bump heads?
比以前少了很多。
时尚是为了放纵。
Much less than before.
Fashion is for indulgence.
我很抱歉剥夺了你伯爵的权利
但我想把你介绍给一个人。
I'm sorry for robbing you of the Count,
but I want to introduce you to someone.
- 先生们。
- Sirs.
亲爱的。
Dear.
最后我给大家介绍一下
基督山伯爵。
Finally, I present to you
the Count of Monte Cristo.
马尔塞夫夫人。我的敬意。
Lady of Morcerf. My respects.
一切都好吗？
Everything is fine?
是的...
Yes, it is...
这就是相遇的感动
没有那个你会哭泣的男人。
It's the emotion of meeting
the man you would cry without.
主啊，我欠你我儿子的命，
Lord, I owe you my son's life,
并为此
好处我祝福你。
and for this
benefit I bless you.
你慷慨地奖励我
一个简单的动作。
You reward me generously
for a simple action.
但我很高兴我
让他免遭痛苦。
But I'm glad I
spared him the pain.
我问伯爵
成为我们的客人，
I asked the count
to be our guest,
但到目前为止他已经拒绝了。
but so far he has refused.
也许你会有更好的运气？
Maybe you'll have better luck?
你能给我快乐吗？
有幸有一天成为我们的客人吗？
Will you give me the pleasure and
honor of one day being our guest?
当然，我的女士。
Certainly, my lady.
让我走开。我会
讨厌垄断你。
Let me move away. I would
hate to monopolize you.
但是……这是怎么回事？
But... what's going on?
你要我打电话给某人吗？
Do you want me to call someone?
阿尔伯特.
Albert.
你对这个人了解多少？
What do you know about this man?
母亲。
Mother.
你总是疑心重重
我的新认识的人，
You are always suspicious
of my new acquaintances,
但伯爵救了我的命。
but the count saved my life.
他像国王一样富有。
He's as rich as a king.
我应该害怕他什么？
What should I fear from him?
你说得对。
You're right.
我的恐惧是愚蠢的。
My terrors are foolish.
金先生的律师，
Mr. King's attorney,
以我的名义，
皇家陆军中尉，
It is on my honor, as
lieutenant of the royal armies,
我在这里证明
爱德蒙·唐太斯这个名字
that I attest here that
the name Edmond Dantès
在我面前作证
曾多次
testified in my presence
on several occasions
对篡位者的同情
of sympathy for the usurper
以及他想要承担的愿望
武装推翻君主制。
and his desire to take up
arms to overthrow the monarchy.
这些话让我印象深刻，因为
爱德蒙唐太斯是我的朋友，
These words impress me because
Edmond Dantès was my friend,
但我不能让这个
犯罪逍遥法外。
But I cannot let this
crime go unpunished.
我见过很多人死去
因为背叛国家的人。
I have seen many men die
because of traitors to the country.
不是这样的
你要睡觉了。
That's not how
you're going to sleep.
我不是在寻找那个。
I wasn't looking for that.
你害怕吗
你的噩梦？
Are you afraid of
your nightmares?
恐怕我不会
有了它了。
I'm afraid I won't
have it anymore.
他们帮助我保持
我的伤口张开。
They help me keep
my wounds open.
你又看到这个了吗？
Have you seen this again?
是的。
Yes.
她有那么美丽吗
正如他记得的那样？
Was she as beautiful
as he remembered?
我以为痛苦
会改变她的。
I thought the pain
would have changed her.
它一定是短暂的。
It must have been short-lived.
她的眼睛不像
经常哭的女人。
Her eyes were not those of a
woman who was crying a lot.
- 她会重新尝到眼泪的味道
当她的丈夫被从她身边夺走时。
- She will regain the taste for tears
when her husband is taken from her.
我通过了。
I pass.
200...
超过500个。
more than 500.
我放弃。
I give up.
我不会邀请你来我的
如果你知道怎么玩的话。
I wouldn't invite you to my
table if you knew how to play.
然后。
Then.
我们只剩下三个人了。
There are only three of us left.
我会让你独自一人。
I'll leave you alone.
两对。
Two pairs.
好工作。
Good job.
颜色。
Color.
它有很多颗心。
It has many hearts.
我要逃跑
在我毁了我父亲之前。
I'm going to run away
before I ruin my father.
- 来吧，艾伯特。
- 是的，就是这样，
- Come on, Albert.
- Yes, that's it,
- 去看看这些女士们。
- 游戏中不快乐，爱情中快乐。
- Go see these ladies.
- Unhappy in the game, happy in love.
我非常喜欢你的王子。
I like your prince very much.
他很有魅力。
He's charming.
老实说，我几乎不认识他。
你父亲是商业关系。
I barely know him, to be honest.
Your father is a business relationship.
一个美好的家庭，这是毫无疑问的。
A good family, without a doubt.
如果“好”意味着“富有”，
是的，这是意大利的第二财富。
If by “good” is meant “rich”,
yes, it is Italy's second fortune.
唔...
Hmm...
第二个？
The second?
那么你知道第一个吗？
So do you know the first one?
别让我不谦虚。
Don't make me immodest.
嗯，比我有钱的人。
Well, people richer than me.
他的家人梦想看到
他在巴黎娶了一个女孩，但是……
His family dreams of seeing
him marry a girl in Paris, but...
如果儿子也这么善变
作为父亲，要小心。
If the son is as fickle
as the father, be careful.
放心，
Rest assured,
总的来说，我不信任每个人。
I distrust everyone in general.
还有来自外国人的，
尤其。
And from foreigners,
in particular.
我也是外国人。
I am also a foreigner.
你，伯爵，那不是
数数。你是一位伯爵。
You, Count, that doesn't
count. You are a Count.
而且还押韵，你见过吗？
And it rhymes, have you seen it?
你是一位诗人。
You are a poet.
关于外国人，
About the foreigner,
公正党被收购
由一个英国人。
L'Impartial was bought
by an Englishman.
绝对地，
Absolutely,
某个哈利法克斯。
看来只有一位主。
a certain Halifax.
One Lord, it seems.
他买报纸
传播假新闻
He buys newspapers
to spread fake news
并推测
股票市场。
and speculate on
the stock market.
他是一个罪犯
最糟糕的一种。
He's a criminal
of the worst kind.
他似乎没有
非常喜欢这位主。
He doesn't seem to
like this Lord very much.
就说我爱吧
很多人，
Let's say I love
a lot of people,
但我只讨厌某些人。
but I only hate certain people.
讨厌英国人是
不是罪过。这是常识。
Hating an Englishman is
not a sin. It's common sense.
你已经走了吗？
Are you leaving already?
已经快半夜了。我们的
马车会变成南瓜。
It's almost midnight. Our
carriage will become a pumpkin.
阿尔伯特.
Albert.
错过。
Miss.
我差点忘了你的扇子。
I was going to forget your fan.
谢谢您，先生。
Thank you, sir.
- 我可以依靠你吗？
- 为了？
- Can I count on you?
- For?
和你一起吃晚饭
Join you for dinner
即将抵达巴黎。
我找到了住的地方。
coming soon to Paris.
I found a place to stay.
嗯...当然，先生。
Well... Of course sir.
好的。
Good.
再见。
See you soon.
数数。
Count.
马尔塞夫夫人。
Lady of Morcerf.
当我到达时它就离开了。
It left when I arrived.
我没有看到任何
连接那里。
I don't see any
connection there.
我想问
你的宽恕。
I wanted to ask for
your forgiveness.
请求我原谅？
Ask me for forgiveness?
因为我那天头晕。
For my dizziness the other day.
这让我想起了一个我
很清楚谁去世了
It reminded me of someone I
knew well who passed away
在悲惨的情况下。
in tragic circumstances.
一瞬间，我...
For a moment, I...
又要开始了，我不行了
不再找到我的话...
It's starting again, I can't
find my words anymore...
抱歉提醒
你那段糟糕的记忆。
I'm sorry to remind
you of that bad memory.
别担心，已经消散了。
Don't worry, it dissipated.
好多了。
So much better.
祝你晚安。
I wish you a good night.
数数。
Count.
马车开走了。
The carriage moves away.
阿尔伯特.
Albert.
“海迪。
“Haydee.
“我不应该给你写信。
所以我不会写信给你。
“I shouldn't write to you.
So I'm not writing to you.
“我不应该认识你……”
"I shouldn't know you..."
因此我并不建议
你们在植物园相遇，
I am therefore not suggesting that
you meet at the Jardin des Plantes,
明天 5 点。
tomorrow at 5 o'clock.
这个地方，我
不会是明天，
This place, where I
won't be tomorrow,
包含最多的
巴黎的神秘花朵。
contains the most
mysterious flowers in Paris.
它来自一个绰号为“
云与茉莉花之地。
It comes from a country nicknamed
the land of clouds and jasmine.
我们可以信赖
巴黎的天空云彩，
We can count on the
Paris sky for clouds,
我会把茉莉花放在我的翻领上。
I'll put jasmine in my lapel.
所以我不会告诉
你直到明天。
So I won't tell
you until tomorrow.
而我并没有告诉过
自从我见到你之后你就这样了
And I haven't been telling
you this since I saw you,
你的声音和你的
脸永远不会离开我。
your voice and your
face never leave me.
阿尔伯特.
Albert.
他不会举报我们吗？
Won't he report us?
他对伯爵非常忠诚
He is very loyal to the count,
但他对我有一个弱点。
but he has a weakness for me.
这是鹤望兰。
It's a strelitzia.
我来自哪里，那里就有
有些在通向大海的小路上。
Where I come from, there were
some on a path that leads to the sea.
它也被称为
天堂鸟，
It is also called
the bird of paradise,
帕萨雷亚天堂。
pasărea paradisului.
帕萨雷亚帕迪苏鲁伊？
Passarea paradisului?
好的。
Good.
他为什么没有新娘？
Why doesn't he have a bride?
但也许有一个？
But maybe there is one?
我父亲希望我
娶男爵的女儿。
My father would like me to
marry a Baron's daughter.
但我...
But I...
我正在寻找这个东西
年轻女人永远不会有。
I'm looking for something this
young woman will never have.
这……无限的魅力就是
女人就像香水之于鲜花。
This... indefinite charm that is to
women what perfume is to flowers.
或者水果的味道如何。
Or what the fruit tastes like.
不知道巴黎人有没有
喜欢被捕捉或品尝，
I don't know if Parisians
like to be caught or tasted,
但不是我。
but not me.
- 我不是这个意思。
- 我在和你开玩笑。
- That's not what I meant.
- I was joking with you.
将会在晚餐时
算星期六吗？
Will be at dinner
Count on Saturday?
不，我将担任
我母亲的不在场证明
No. I'll serve as an
alibi for my mother
谁逃离世俗
就像瘟疫一样。
who flees worldliness
like the plague.
你呢？
And you?
我不认识你妈妈
I don't know your mother,
我不知道什么
她的品味是
I don't know what
her tastes are,
但我和你一样厌恶。
But I share your disgust.
无论是他还是他的
妈妈会来吃晚饭。
Neither he nor his
mother will come to dinner.
但费尔南德
马尔塞夫将会在那里。
But Fernand de
Morcerf will be there.
有什么问题吗？
What's the problem?
你不是在说话吗
给我关于艾伯特的事？
Aren't you talking
to me about Albert?
什么都没有
说到这一点。
There's nothing
to say about that.
有怀疑是很正常的。
It's normal to doubt.
害怕。我明白这一点。
Be afraid. I understand that.
但当时机到来时，
你需要记住...
But when the time comes,
you need to remember...
我不需要
I don't need
提醒我什么
他父亲对我做了。
to remind me of what
his father did to mine.
他把嘴唇放在那里。
He placed his lips there.
谢谢
Thanks
- 非常昂贵。
- 当然。
- Very expensive.
- Of course.
亲爱的朋友们。
Dear friends.
晚上好，维多利亚。
Good evening, Victoria.
我也期待着
更加壮观，
I also expected
more spectacular,
没有意义
在做那张脸时。
There's no point
in making that face.
肯定会有
里面会有惊喜。
There will definitely
be surprises inside.
宝宝在哭。
The baby is crying.
唔...
Hmm...
他似乎没有
胃口很大。
He doesn't seem to
have much of an appetite.
我吃过猪肉和家禽。
I've eaten pork and poultry.
这房子……很漂亮。
This house is... beautiful.
尽管发生了一切，
我感到很惊讶。
Despite everything,
I feel surprised.
没有什么能逃过他的眼睛。
Nothing escapes him.
我以为像你这样的男人会
选择更中心的街区，
I thought a man like you would
choose a more central neighborhood,
就像……香榭丽舍大街
或圣日耳曼。
like... the Champs-Elysées
or Saint-Germain.
我买这个房子是因为
有人建议我不要这样做。
I bought this house because
I was advised against it.
为了什么？
For what?
嗯，他们说这里闹鬼。
Well, they say it's haunted.
犯罪将会发生
那里……可恶，几年前。
A crime would have happened
there... Abominable, years ago.
小心点，我们有
国王检察官在这里。
Be careful, we have the
King's Procurator here.
和真相。
And truth.
一个孩子将会有
被牺牲了。
A child will have
been sacrificed.
太可怕了。
It's horrible.
你到底买了这个房子吗？
Did you buy this house anyway?
你做得很好。
You did well.
这些鬼故事纯属无稽之谈
These ghost stories are nonsense
由恶意的仆人发明的。
invented by malicious servants.
或者嫉妒的邻居。
Or jealous neighbors.
再想一想，检察官。
Think again, Prosecutor.
我住在亚洲和印度，
I lived in Asia and India,
很难再回来
不知道它确实存在
and it's hard to come back from
this without knowing that it really exists
一个世界...
a world...
看不见的，充满了灵魂。
invisible, populated by spirits.
当我参观这所房子时，...
When I visited this house,...
我立刻就知道了...
I knew immediately...
我有一种奇怪的信念
这里曾发生过犯罪行为。
I had the strange conviction that
a crime had been committed here.
所以我问
So I asked
- 直到我独自一人。
- 但...
- until I'm alone.
- But...
你不害怕吗？
weren't you scared?
如果你的良心是纯洁的，
鬼魂不会困扰你。
If your conscience is pure,
ghosts don't haunt you.
他们跟你说话。
They talk to you.
-他们告诉你什么了？
- 但是，是的，他们告诉了你什么？
-And what did they tell you?
- But yes, what did they tell you?
那天晚上，我就定居在这里。
That night, I settled here.
就在前面
那个壁炉的。
Right in front
of that fireplace.
我吸了一点鸦片
变得更容易接受。
I smoked a little opium
to be more receptive.
没有什么比它更能扩展
你的意识范围。
There is nothing like it to expand
the spectrum of your consciousness.
而在甜蜜中
烟雾的...
And in the sweetness
of the smoke...
我感觉就像……暂停了。
I felt like... suspended.
我听到敲墙声。
I hear a knock on the walls.
然后一秒钟。
Then a second.
我放下手。
I lowered my hand.
我听到尖叫声传来
从上面。我走上楼梯。
And I hear screams coming
from above. I go up the stairs.
尖叫声变成了……呻吟。
The screams turn into... moans.
来自一个房间
Comes from a room
在走廊的尽头。
at the end of the corridor.
我推门然后
发现自己在一个房间里。
I push the door and
find myself in a room.
中间有一张床。
In the middle there is a bed.
我把手放在那里。
I put my hand there.
我看到一个女人
痛苦地翻滚。
And I see a woman
writhing in pain.
她生下了一个孩子。
她孤身一人，被抛弃了。
She gives birth to a child.
She's alone, abandoned.
她尖叫起来。
She screams.
然后我感觉
在我背后的存在。
And then I feel a
presence behind my back.
突然。
Suddenly.
你吓坏了这些女士。
You terrify these ladies.
你让我们着迷。
And you enchant us.
继续吧，我求你了。
Carry on, I beg you.
来吧，你是
破坏聚会。
Come on, you're
ruining the party.
我转过身，浑身发抖。
I turn around, shaking.
而此时此刻，
And at this moment,
我听到耳边有声音。
I hear a whisper in my ear.
这是一个孩子的声音。
It's a child's voice.
一个孩子的声音在哀求我
A child's voice begging me
释放他。
to free him.
终于找到了一扇门，
Finally I found a door,
我没见过的后门。
a back door I hadn't seen.
我推她。
I push her.
楼梯...通向花园。
Stairs... Lead to the garden.
而她回来了，
孩子的声音。
And she came back,
the child's voice.
他告诉我他一直孤身一人
许久。他在哭。
He told me he had been alone
for a long time. He was crying.
他打电话给他的母亲。
He calls his mother.
那天晚上，我...
That night, I...
我看了看，但是……
I looked, but...
花园很大。
the garden was very big.
什么...你做了什么？
What... What did you do?
饶恕？
Forgiveness?
花园很大...
The garden was very big...
你做了什么？
What did you do?
是的。
Yes.
第二天早上我们就挖了。
The next morning we dug.
到处。
Everywhere.
我们把苹果连根拔起
树，我返回了路径......
We uprooted the apple
trees, I returned the path...
什么也没有。
And nothing.
所以我带了一块松露
来自佩里戈尔的猪。
So I brought a truffled
pig from Périgord.
所以呢？
So what?
既然他没有
找到任何东西，
Since he didn't
find anything either,
我们今晚吃了饭。
we ate tonight.
精彩的！
Wonderful!
我说这只是一个寓言。
I said it was just a fable.
确切地说，是一个寓言。
A fable, exactly.
至少我是这样的
想法。直到昨天。
At least that's what I
thought. Until yesterday.
当我们被殖民时
While we were colonized
接待处的火把，
the torches for the reception,
其中一个坏了。
one of them broke.
我们在那里挖了然后...
We dug there and...
我们发现了一个箱子。
we discovered a chest.
所以呢？
So what?
里面是什么？
What was inside?
我不知道。
I don't know.
像这样？
Like this?
我等着它……打开。
I waited for it... to open.
如果有尸体怎么办？
What if there is a body?
我们将为您举行葬礼。
We will give you a burial.
检察官，你可能希望
Prosecutor, you may wish
打开它？
open it?
- 我求你了，别打开它。
- 够了。
- I beg you, don't open it.
- That's enough.
胡言乱语！
Abracadabra!
哦，我不知道
Oh, I don't know
这就是这个故事中的真实情况，
但你是一个魔术师，
which is true in this story,
but you are a magician,
数数。
Count.
怎么可能呢？他
说话就好像他就在场一样。
How is it possible? He
spoke as if he were there.
所有这些细节...我
我以为我要疯了。
All these details were... I
thought I was going crazy.
请冷静。
Calm down, please.
- 我们儿子的尸体在哪里？
- 我不知道。
- Where is our son's body?
- I don't know.
- 你把它放在那里了吗？
- 是的。
- Did you put it there?
- Yes.
你告诉我他是
死的！你告诉我了！
You told me he was
dead! You told me!
他当然死了。
Of course he was dead.
- 那么他在哪里？
- 我不知道。
- So where is he?
- I don't know.
- 我们的儿子在哪里？
- 我不知道！
- Where is our son?
- I don't know!
闭嘴，你是
歇斯底里！我不知道。
Shut up, you're
hysterical! I don't know.
冷静下来。
Calm down.
我知道一件事。
I know one thing.
只是这样
八天前，
It's just that
before eight days,
我会知道这是谁
基督山先生是，
I will know who this
Mr. Monte Cristo is,
它从哪里来
从哪里来，到哪里去，
where it comes
from, where it goes,
以及为什么他在众人面前讲话
我们谈论我们埋葬的孩子们。
and why he talks in front of
us about the children we buried.
腾格拉尔痴迷于金钱。
Danglars is obsessed with money.
他不会怀疑
He won't suspect
来自那些不这样做的人
要求它。马尔塞夫
from those who don't
ask for it. Morcerf
相信我，因为我救了你的儿子。
Trust me since I saved your son.
维尔福依然存在。
Villefort remains.
维尔福是检察官。
Villefort is the Prosecutor.
他很怀疑。
He is suspicious.
也感谢这顿晚餐，
维多利亚将要求做出解释。
And thanks to this dinner,
Victoria will demand explanations.
所以为了让她放心
并安慰自己，
So, to reassure her
and reassure herself,
他会调查。
he will investigate.
正如我们一直学习的那样
更多来自恶意之口，
And as we always learn
more from malicious mouths,
这是伯爵的
他将看到的敌人。
it is the Count's
enemy that he will see.
哈利法克斯先生。
Mr Halifax.
你想知道什么？
What do you want to know?
如果我可以伤害你
这将是一种乐趣。
If I can harm you,
it will be a pleasure.
计数已经
去过巴黎吗？他声称没有。
The count has already
been in Paris? He claims no.
如果他已经
在这里，我会知道。
If he was already
here, I would know.
但那么你知道吗
15年前他在哪里？
But then, do you know
where he was 15 years ago?
是的。在印度。
Yes. In India.
但...
But...
我必须说，
I must say,
当时他还逗我笑。
At the time, he still amused me.
但后来...
But then...
然后呢？
Then what?
有一天晚上我在
纠正仆人
One night I was
correcting a servant
谁找得好。
who had looked for it well.
但...
But...
基督山开发了
对这些野蛮人的热情，
Monte Cristo developed a
passion for these savages,
和它的异教诸神，
这是荒谬的魔法。
with its pagan gods,
its absurd magic.
可笑的信念。
Ridiculous beliefs.
然后他向我发起决斗挑战。
Then he challenged me to a duel.
是本地人做的吗？
By a native?
但是是的！本地人！
But yes! A native!
你能相信吗？
Can you believe it?
哦。
Oh.
天气很热，你不
思考？多热啊！
It's hot, don't you
think? How hot!
我被带到我的粉丝身边，
为了天堂的爱！
I am brought to my fan,
for the love of heaven!
我们在这里快要窒息了！
We're suffocating here!
不是这个。
Not this one.
谢谢。
Thanks.
唔。你呢，
Hmm. And you,
维尔福勋爵？
Lord de Villefort?
他对你做了什么？
What did he do to you?
没有什么。
Nothing.
我不知道我是否应该考虑
他在我的朋友或我的敌人中。
I don't know whether I should consider
him among my friends or among my enemies.
如果他是你的敌人
你应该已经知道了。
If he were your enemy,
you would already know that.
他有缺点，但他没有
一个隐藏自己意图的人。
He has flaws, but he is not
a man to hide his intentions.
唔。
Hmm.
但...
But...
小心。
take care.
检察官先生。
Mr Prosecutor.
如果他成为你的朋友，
If he becomes your friend,
那会让你成为我的敌人。
that will make you my enemy.
当然。
Of course.
是的。
Yes.
谢谢德先生
维尔福，非常愉快
Thank you, Mr. de
Villefort, It was very pleasant
与您讨论,
但我还有很多事要做。
discuss with you,
but I have a lot to do.
谢谢。
Thanks.
检察官先生。
Mr Prosecutor.
胜利者。
Victor.
数数？
Count?
准备
马，我们回去吧。
Prepare the
horses, let's go back.
现在维尔福
放松了警惕，
Now that Villefort
has let his guard down,
我们可以准备进攻了。
we can prepare our attack.
我要去南方。
I'm going south.
我要回去参加腾格拉尔的派对
为他女儿20岁生日。
I'm going back to Danglars' party
for his daughter's 20th birthday.
我指望你，
I'm counting on you,
安德烈，为了离她更近一些。
André, to get closer to her.
而你，海黛，
迷惑阿尔伯特。
And in you, Haydée,
to bewitch Albert.
前进。
Go ahead.
好的。
Good.
最多可容纳600人
黑人，700 有点推动，但是......
It can accommodate up to 600
blacks, 700 pushing a little, but...
我是一个人文主义者。
I am a humanist.
我称他为赫拉克勒斯。
I called him Hercules.
我妈说这是血统
注定成就伟大事业的人。
My mother said this is the lineage
of people destined for great things.
这就是你的……爱情短语。
And that's your... love phrase.
然后我读到了这个...
And then I read this...
我必须告诉你一件事。
I have to tell you something.
是的？
Yes?
我愿意爱你，
I would like to love you,
- 但我不能。
- 我知道。
- but I can't.
- I know.
你不会向我提供
You won't offer me
他对苏珊娜的感情。
the feelings he has for Suzanne.
这将是我们的秘密。
It will be our secret.
它将被妥善保存。
It will be well kept.
我知道那是什么
喜欢成双。
I know what it's
like to be double.
我知道那是什么
喜欢成双。
I know what it's
like to be double.
因无法
说出我们是谁。
Of not being able
to say who we are.
我会成为你的不在场证明。
I'll be your alibi.
时机已到
来救赎自己。
The time has come
to redeem yourself.
听不见的话
Inaudible words
我又活在梦里了
I live again in dreams
这些的每一秒
和你在一起的时刻。
every second of these
moments with you.
我会带走记忆
你的眼睛进入我的夜晚，
I will take the memory
of your eyes into my night,
我不想
与任何人交谈
and I don't want
to talk to anyone
以免浪费
你话语的回声
so as not to waste
the echo of your words
至今仍在我心中颤抖。
that still trembles in my heart.
我保留你的单子
音乐离我很近。
I keep your sheet
music close to me.
我喜欢这个形象
你给我你，
I love the image
you give me of you,
但也最重要的是
她将永远铭记的记忆
but also and above all for the
memory that she will carry forever,
生命中的某个时刻
那是值得一生的。
that of a moment in life
that is worth a lifetime.
嗡嗡声
buzz
- 稍后见。
- See you later.
王子。
Prince.
尤金妮.这个聚会是在
你的形象，生机勃勃，充满欢乐。
Eugénie. This party is in
your image, alive and joyful.
谢谢你，安德里亚。
Thank you, Andrea.
它将包括计数
您的客人中有基督山吗？
It will include the Count of
Monte Christ among your guests?
17.
17？
17?
你是第17个
问我这个问题。
You are the 17th to
ask me the question.
大家的回答是什么？
And what does everyone answer?
那将会有
没有18号。就在那里。
That there will be
no 18th. There it is.
- 打扰一下。
- Excuse me.
错过。
miss.
- 数数。 你的旅行还顺利吗？
- 太棒了。
- Count. Did your trip go well?
- Wonderfully.
- 谢谢。
- 尤金妮很不耐烦
- Thanks.
- Eugénie is impatient
再次见到你，小姐。
to see you again, miss.
伯爵，你允许我吗？
Count, will you allow me?
快乐是我的。
The pleasure is mine.
伯爵知道吗
我们看到对方了吗？
Does the count know
we saw each other?
我什么也没告诉你。
I didn't tell you anything.
- 他能猜到吗？
- 只有上帝知道他的能力。
- Could he have guessed?
- Only God knows what he is capable of.
它们很漂亮，不是吗？
They're beautiful, aren't they?
他们看起来非常渴望生活。
They seem so eager to live.
我们始终在
急着要快乐。
We are always in
a hurry to be happy.
不？
No?
请赐予我你的手臂的荣誉。
Do me the honor of your arm.
我想采取一些措施。
I want to take some steps.
你的手在颤抖。
Your hand is shaking.
他似乎很冷。
He seems to be cold.
我们家有，
手冰冷，心却温暖。
We have, in my family,
cold hands but warm heart.
这里。这会让我们温暖起来。
Here. That will warm us up.
我们的葡萄是
比西西里岛还糟糕
Our grapes are
worse than in Sicily
但会很宽容
与我们北方的太阳。
but it will be lenient
with our northern sun.
对不起。
I'm sorry.
请原谅我，但是……
Please forgive me, but...
我从来不喝酒。
I never drink.
你要吃点东西吗？
Are you going to eat something?
我又得拒绝了
I'll have to refuse again.
康德先生，有一个阿拉伯人
结交永远朋友的习俗
Mr. Conde, there is an Arab
custom that makes friends forever
那些分享面包的人
和盐在同一屋檐下。
those who shared bread
and salt under the same roof.
我认识你，女士。
I know you, ma'am.
但我们在巴黎
而不是丹吉尔。
But we are in Paris
and not Tangier.
不再有永恒的友谊
在这里比分享面包和盐更重要。
There is no more eternal friendship
here than sharing bread and salt.
但最后...我们
朋友们，不是吗？
But finally... We're
friends, aren't we?
但绝对是。
But definitely.
我们为什么不呢？
Why wouldn't we be?
所以，在没有面包的情况下，
盐，与我分享一些回忆。
So, in the absence of bread and
salt, Share with me some memories.
你想知道什么？
What do you want to know?
确实，看了这么多，
It's true that you saw so much,
我旅行了那么多，
I traveled so much,
受了这么多苦？
suffered so much?
是什么让你这么说？
What makes you say that?
你的眼睛。
Your eyes.
每个旅人心里都有
渴望找到或逃避某事。
In every traveler there is the
desire to find or escape something.
你找到了吗？
Did you find it?
我还没有完成我的旅行。
I haven't finished my trip yet.
你独自生活吗？
Do you live alone?
我没有妹妹
既不是儿子，也不是父亲。
I don't have a sister,
neither son nor father.
我只有海黛，
我确信，很快就会离开我。
I only have Haydée who,
I'm sure, will leave me soon.
你怎么能这样生活
How can you live like this,
没有任何东西
将你与生活联系起来？
without anything to
connect you to life?
我爱过一个年轻女孩。
I loved a young girl.
说我要结婚了。
That I was going to get married.
几年前。
Years ago.
但当战争来临的时候
并把我从它身边带走...
But when the war came
and took me away from it...
我以为她会爱
我足够等我了。
I thought she would love
me enough to wait for me.
保持忠诚
对我来说，直到坟墓。
To remain faithful
to me until the grave.
但当我回来后，
But when I came back,
结婚了。
was married.
也许他有更弱的
心比别人强。
Maybe he had a weaker
heart than the others.
我所受的苦超过
他们会受苦的
I suffered more than
they would have suffered
- 就这样。
——这份爱还留在你心里吗？
- That's all.
- Did this love remain in your heart?
我们只真正喜欢过一次。
We only really loved it once.
不？
No?
你又见到她了吗？
Did you see her again?
绝不。
Never.
绝不？
Never?
绝不。
Never.
你原谅了吗
他的痛苦？
Did you forgive
him his suffering?
我们只能原谅那些
谁请求我们宽恕。
We can only forgive those
who ask us for forgiveness.
如果她问你怎么办
今天求宽恕吗？
What if she asked you
for forgiveness today?
- 购买 L'Impartial！舰队
腾格拉尔从马赛被盗！
- Buy L'Impartial! The fleet
Danglars stolen from Marseille!
不偏不倚，女士们，
先生们！公正！
L'Impartial, ladies and
gentlemen! L'Impartial!
买！
Buy!
船怎么会被偷
光天化日之下从港口出发？
How can boats be stolen
from a port in broad daylight?
他们至少有保险吗？
Were they at least insured?
您认为？
In your opinion?
腾格拉尔股价暴跌
在股票市场上。
Danglars shares collapse
on the stock market.
但感谢
陆军电报、
But thanks to the
army telegraph,
腾格拉尔学得很快
真的什么都没发生。
Danglars will quickly learn
that nothing really happened.
你必须偷他的船。
You had to steal his boats.
一切都到了
等待者的时间到了。
Everything arrives on
time for those who wait.
你得救了。他们的
船什么都没有。
You are saved. Their
boats have nothing.
- 什么？
- 公正的人撒了谎。
- What?
- L'Imparcial lied.
“腾格拉尔舰队仍然
"The Danglars fleet is still
“漂浮在停泊处
马赛港”！
“afloat moored in
the port of Marseille”!
谢谢。谢谢你们，我的朋友们。
Thanks. Thank you, my friends.
腾格拉尔会记得
我的话和我的想法...
Danglars will remember
my words and think...
这是由
L'Impartial 的新老板，
Which is a move by the
new boss of L'Impartial,
我们亲爱的哈利法克斯勋爵。
our dear Lord Halifax.
确切地。
Exactly.
基督山是对的。
Monte Cristo was right.
英国人用他的
报纸来猜测我的背影。
The Englishman uses his
newspaper to speculate about my back.
你应该发表否认这一点的文章。
You should publish denying this.
尤其不是。
Especially not.
我不明白。
有必要...
I don't understand.
It is necessary...
嘘！
Shh!
你听到了吗？
Do you hear?
听。
Listen.
令人愉快的噪音。
The pleasant noise.
那可口的小噪音。
That tasty little noise.
金钱掉落的声音。
The sound of falling money.
我也不明白。
I don't understand either.
想一想。他知道
尚无人知晓的事情。
Think about it. He knows
something that no one knows yet.
想象一下：你玩扑克并且
了解对手的比赛。
Imagine: you play poker and
know your opponent's game.
- 你在干什么？
- 我会重新开始。
- What are you doing?
- I'll restart.
股票现价为
他们的最低水平。
Stocks are at
their lowest level.
如果你过两天再买的话
将创造巨大的附加值。
If you buy them again in two days, I
will have made enormous added value.
我最好的机会。
My best chance.
回购你的股票？
Buy back your shares?
需要多少钱？
How much would be needed?
- 5亿。
- 5亿？
- 500 million.
- 500 million?
5亿。但它
今天必须完成。
500 million. But it
must be done today.
收市前及
在这个哈利法克斯败类之前。
Before the market closes and
before this Halifax scum does.
我们怎样才能找到
今晚就五亿？
How can we find
500 million by tonight?
要去见主
哈利法克斯最大的敌人。
Going to see Lord
Halifax's greatest enemy.
对不起，男爵，但是……
I'm sorry, Baron, but...
大海一直
给我带来了厄运。
the sea has always
brought me bad luck.
我不会买你的股票。
I'm not buying your shares.
- 数数。
- 然而，
- Count.
- However,
我从不拒绝帮助
朋友并惩罚敌人。
I never refuse to help a
friend and punish an enemy.
然后我会把钱借给你
你可以用它做任何你想做的事。
Then I will lend you that money and
you can do with it whatever you want.
而且我可以保证
20%的利率。
And I can guarantee
a 20% interest rate.
我借给你
钱无息。
I will lend you
money interest free.
在西西里岛，人们说：
In Sicily they say:
“你不会变得富有
是在朋友的背后。”
“You won’t get rich
off the back of a friend.”
我坚持。
I insist.
我有抵押贷款
以我的所有资产发行。
I had a mortgage
issued on all my assets.
因此，它不是
价值五亿，但是……
Therefore, it is not
worth 500 million, but...
2亿，
就是这样，我保证。
200 million,
that's it, I promise.
不，男爵，你的
一句话对我来说就足够了。
No, Baron, your
word is enough for me.
在法国我们说：
In France we say:
“好账
结交好朋友。”
“Good accounts
make good friends.”
就这样吧。为了友谊，我
接受您的个人保证。
So be it. For friendship, I
accept your personal guarantees.
一周后，我将
你报销了吗？
In a week, I will
have you reimbursed.
让我们把这个人
哈利法克斯投降。
Let's make this man
from Halifax surrender.
投诉已准备就绪。
A complaint is ready.
我会注意我所带来的
我本人在审判中对他提出指控。
I will see to it that I bring
charges against him at trial myself.
我迫不及待地想出庭
见证这次处决。
I can't wait to be in court
to witness this execution.
哈利法克斯勋爵，
L'Impartial 的所有者，
Lord Halifax,
owner of L'Impartial,
今天被传唤出庭作证
called to testify today
回应
诽谤指控，
to respond to
accusations of defamation,
他不得不离开
国家着急。
he had to leave the
country in a hurry.
但您承诺确保
您的代表
But you undertake to ensure
that your representative
下午 2 点到这个法庭
be in this courtroom at 2 p.m.
喜剧《法官先生》
已经持续足够长的时间了。
Mr. Judge, the comedy
has gone on long enough.
我们不在林荫大道上。
We are not on the boulevards.
我问代表
哈利法克斯先生自我介绍。
I ask the representative of
Mr Halifax introduce himself.
你在干什么？
事情还没有结束。
What are you doing?
It's not over yet.
我是哈利法克斯勋爵的
代表。
I am Lord Halifax's
representative.
我在你面前
I'm in front of you
因为 L'Impartial 受到指控
发布假新闻。
because L'Impartial is accused
of having published fake news.
但我在这里说
But I say here
腾格拉尔船
实际上已经消失了。
that the Danglars boats
have effectively disappeared.
无论如何，我的舰队
就在马赛！
Anyway, my fleet
is in Marseille!
这是一个笑话！
It's a joke!
- 你有什么证据？
- 这对你来说就足够了
- What proof do you have?
- It will be enough for you
联系
马赛队长。
to contact the
Marseille captaincy.
那么你是否坚持
在你的陈述中？
So do you persist
in your statements?
我坚持并签字，法官先生。
I persist and sign, Mr Judge.
但我想做
以我的真实姓名。
But I want to do it
under my real name.
你是骗子吗？
Are you an impostor?
人们都知道我是
安德里亚·卡瓦尔坎蒂
People know me as
Andrea Cavalcanti.
经过多年的
街头，我被一个大
After years on the
streets, I was taken by a big
和富裕的家庭
意大利贵族。
and rich family of
the Italian aristocracy.
我像小偷一样长大
I grew up like a thief
我最终
成为王子。
and I ended up
becoming a prince.
这不是一个更诚实的职业，
但更令人愉快。
It is not a more honest profession,
but much more enjoyable.
正是在这里，在巴黎，我
终于找到了我的亲生父亲。
It's here, in Paris, that I
finally found my real father.
我出生于 1815 年 11 月 3 日。
I was born on November 3, 1815.
在奥特伊。
In Auteuil.
法官，就这样吧……
Judge, that's it...
被告人能否出庭
证明他的主张？
Could the defendant present
proof of what he claims?
我马上就到，
先生。律师。
I'll be right there,
sir. Attorney.
你的耐心将会得到回报。
Your patience will be rewarded.
我是法国人的私生子
贵族和他的情妇！
I'm the bastard son of a French
aristocrat and his mistress!
我妈妈不知道
我还活着，因为……我的父亲
My mother doesn't know
I'm alive because... my father
我告诉他我
出生时就去世了。
I told him that I
had died at birth.
他把我包裹在一个
布把我活埋了。
He wrapped me in a
cloth and buried me alive.
先生，它讲的是一个
企图杀婴。
It speaks, sir, of an
attempt at infanticide.
这就是应该发生的事情
That's what should have happened
如果我阿姨没有选择
我从地上起来。
if my aunt hadn't picked
me up off the ground.
谁在指责？
Who is accusing?
一个值得尊敬的人...
A respectable man...
你们都知道。
that you all know.
他的手臂在这块亚麻布里。
His arm is in this linen.
我的父亲...
My father...
正是
我面前有一个人。
is none other than the
man I have before me.
维尔福检察官。
The Prosecutor of Villefort.
- 或者我会撤离房间。
- 诽谤！
- Or I'll evacuate the room.
- Slander!
我要起诉你！
I will sue you!
卡瓦尔坎蒂先生，
Mr Cavalcanti,
你明白吗
你的指控的严重性？
Do you understand the
seriousness of your accusations?
我不会满足于一块布，
即使沾满了血。
I will not be satisfied with a cloth,
even if it is stained with blood.
检察官将提供
你有我所说的证据。
The prosecutor will provide
you with proof of what I say.
- 但他神志不清！
- 父亲。
- But he's delirious!
- Father.
别让我妈妈出庭作证
Don't make my mother testify.
我认为她有
受够了。
She, I think, has
suffered enough.
审判暂停
The trial is suspended
调查的时间。
我们撤离房间吧！
the time of an investigation.
Let's evacuate the room!
还有一个。
And one.
-来吧，维多利亚，来吧！
-饶恕。
-Come on, Victoria, come on!
-Forgiveness.
让我们过去。
Let us through.
你为什么不
告诉我真相吗？
Why didn't you
tell me the truth?
你父亲想要我
作为他的女婿，但是……
Your father wanted me
as his son-in-law, but...
我不可能是你的
妈妈也是我的。
I couldn't be, your
mother is mine too.
不要忘记你的生命线。
Don't forget your lifelines.
姐姐要幸福啊
Be happy, sister.
数数！
Count!
这个故事毫无意义。
我们在精神错乱中游泳。
This story makes no sense.
We are swimming in delirium.
我的船，昨天，
仍在马赛。我...
My boats, yesterday,
were still in Marseilles. I...
我需要一个...
偿还期限。
I'm going to need a...
a deadline to repay it.
如果...
If...
什么都没有了，男爵。
There's nothing left, Baron.
一切
是你的就是我的。
Everything that
was yours is mine.
他唯一拥有的东西
剩下的是这些衣服。
The only thing he has
left are these clothes.
离开巴黎也许
不离开你的妻子
Leave Paris and maybe
not leave your wife
他的女儿也饿死了。
and his daughter dies of hunger.
但无论如何，告诉我，我...
But anyway, tell me, I...
你认为我很残忍吗，男爵？
Do you think I'm brutal, Baron?
不仅我知道，
Not only do I know that,
但我吹嘘它。
but I brag about it.
呼吸不稳定
Unstable breathing
你应该带你的妻子回家。
You should take your wife home.
她的脸色非常苍白。
She is very pale.
还有两个。
And two.
父亲！
Father!
作者：安吉拉.
By Angèle.
走开!
Get out of the way!
不！
No!
为了什么？
For what?
别哭。
Don't cry.
我们就知道事情会这样结束。
We knew it would end like this.
我们知道这一点。
We knew that.
海蒂！
Haydee!
他不服从。
He disobeyed.
你违抗了吗？
Did you disobey?
你违背了什么？
What did you disobey?
这只会教会他仇恨。
It only taught him hate.
他把那
他手中的匕首。
He placed that
dagger in his hand.
这是你的痛苦在说话。
It is your pain that speaks.
我爱他就像爱儿子一样。
I loved him like a son.
嘲笑声
mocking laughter
黑暗音乐
Dark music
你也爱我吗？
Do you love me too?
我也是，你准备好了吗
牺牲我来报仇？
Me too, are you ready to
sacrifice me for your revenge?
这不是报复。
It's not revenge.
这是正义。
It's justice.
别忘了你的泪水
海黛，你母亲的哭泣
Don't forget your tears,
Haydée, Your mother's cry
和你父亲的血。
and your father's blood.
以及名字
背叛他们的人。
And the name of the
person who betrayed them.
别忘了他的名字！
Don't forget his name!
如果你爱我
If you love me
既然我爱你，就不要
尝试再次见到我。
As I love you, don't
try to see me again.
他太高贵了
心里不明白。
He's too noble of
heart not to understand.
我保持我的力量
与自己战斗并喝下我的眼泪。
I maintain my strength to
fight myself and drink my tears.
远离快乐
我，你值得拥有。
Be happy away from
me, you deserve it.
阿尔伯特？
Albert?
阿尔伯特.
Albert.
你疯了。
You are crazy.
你不能留下来。
You can't stay.
海黛，我只是
认识你有一段时间了...
Haydée, I've only
known you for a while...
留下它。
Leave it.
像一个人一样逃离我
逃离瘟疫。
Flee from me like one
fleeing from the plague.
- 我会让你不高兴。
- 但跟我一起逃吧。
- I'm going to make you unhappy.
- But run away with me.
我向你发誓，海黛，
I swear to you, Haydée,
这不是绝望，而是
我向你承诺的幸福。
Instead of despair, This is
the happiness I promise you.
你不认识我。
伯爵不知道。
You don't know me.
The Count doesn't know.
海蒂...
Haydee...
如果你爱我
就像我爱你一样...
If you love me
like I love you...
告诉我再见。
Tell me goodbye.
我求求你。
I beg you.
说！
Say!
所以我会告诉你
So I'll tell you
向阅读的上帝证明
我的内心深处...
attesting to God, who reads
the depths of my heart...
祝你快乐
没有我记忆的生活。
I wish you a happy
life without my memory.
再见，我的爱人。
Goodbye, my love.
这个样子。
This look.
没有你，我的生命就失去了。
Without you my life is lost.
我的不幸，对吧。
My misfortune, right.
你会怎样做？
What are you going to do?
但请放心，我
我会遵守诺言。
But rest assured, I
will keep my promise.
但拜托，你会活下去吗？
But please, will you live?
什么对你来说很重要？
What is important to you?
在你眼里，我已经死了。
In your eyes, I am already dead.
让我们逃跑。
Let's run away.
海迪。
Haydee.
如果你想加入
马尔塞夫家族，
If you want to join
the Morcerf family,
阿尔伯特值得知道
Albert deserves to know
你的故事。
your story.
如果你保持沉默，我就会
被迫代替你说话。
If you remain silent, I will be
forced to speak in your place.
我真的需要谈谈
I really need to talk
以你的名义？
in your name?
请告诉我。
Tell me, please.
海黛就是那个女孩……
Haydée is the girl...
停止！
Stop!
我会说话。
I will speak.
黑暗音乐
Dark music
我的父亲是一位杰出的
这个人名叫阿里·特贝林 (Ali Tebelin)。
My father was an illustrious
man known as Ali Tebelin.
贾尼娜帕夏。
Pasha of Janina.
我当时10岁
I was 10 years old
当他之前被杀的时候
我的眼睛和我母亲的眼睛。
when he was killed before
my eyes and my mother's.
接收一名法国士兵
Received a French soldier
谁是我们的盟友。
who was our ally.
被十几颗子弹射穿，
Pierced by a dozen bullets,
我的父亲
my father
找到了站立的力量
found the strength to stand
并射杀了卖掉它的人
and shot the man who sold it
挖出眼睛。
gouging out the eye.
我再也没有见过我的母亲。
I never saw my mother again.
这位官员卖了
我沦为奴隶
This officer sold
me into slavery
巴尔干地区的一个瓦拉几部落。
to a Vlach tribe in the Balkans.
- 他的名字是...
- 够了。
- His name was...
- That's enough.
阿尔伯特.
Albert.
- 你操纵了我。
- 我警告过你。
- You manipulated me.
- I warned you.
- 你利用了我。
- 你可能会后悔你的话。
- You used me.
- You may regret your words.
- 你觉得你在吓唬我吗？
- 别激怒我。
- Do you think you're scaring me?
- Don't provoke me.
阿尔伯特，请。
Albert, please.
数数！
Count!
它夺走了我的一切。
除了我的名字，你弄脏了。
It took everything away from me.
Except my name, which you dirty.
不！
No!
哦，伯爵，我求求你了。
Oh, Count, I beg you.
我认为你的手套被丢弃了。
I consider your glove discarded.
我会把它卷起来还给你
明天打个球。
I'll return it to you rolled
up in a ball tomorrow.
你不后悔吗？
Aren't you sorry?
他们有没有
爱德蒙唐太斯？
Did they have any
for Edmond Dantès?
看着我。
Look at me.
我只不过是
聋哑人武装手臂致死。
I am nothing more than the
armed arm of deaf and blind fatality.
费尔南·德·马尔塞夫将体验
我父亲的经历。
Fernand de Morcerf will experience
what my father experienced.
如果你杀了艾伯特
If you kill Albert,
你将不再能够
说：“神帮助我，与我同在。”
you will no longer be able to
say: “God is for me, with me.”
他将成为一名杀手。
He will be a killer.
圣经说，孩子们
将为父母的罪行付出代价。
The Bible says that children
will pay for their parents' crimes.
雅各布，跟着她。
Jacopo, follow her.
他带着枪。
He carries his gun.
离开我们吧，雅各布。
Leave us, Jacopo.
女士。
Madam.
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
埃德蒙，你
不会杀死我的儿子。
Edmond, you
will not kill my son.
你说的是什么名字？
What name did you say?
你的。
Yours.
不是马尔塞夫夫人
Not Madame de Morcerf
谁在前面
你是梅赛德斯。
who is in front of
you is Mercédès.
我谁也不认识
用那个名字。
I don't know anyone
with that name.
我认出你是
我一看到你。
I recognized you as
soon as I saw you.
即使没有见到你，我
会认出你的声音。
And even without seeing you, I
would have recognized your voice.
我的理智很挣扎，但我的心
知道。从那时起，我就一直关注他，
My reason was struggling, but my heart
knew. Since then, I have been following him,
看着他，寻找
他想要马尔塞夫做什么。
watching him, looking for
what he wants with Morcerf.
费尔南德，我是说，女士。
Fernand, I mean, ma'am.
既然我们还记得
我们的名字。
Since we can remember
our first names.
我应该受到责备。
I'm to blame.
是我缺乏力量
面对你的缺席。
It was I who lacked strength
in the face of your absence.
我就是那个
当你死的时候缺乏信心。
I was the one who
lacked faith when you died.
- 我的！
- 为了什么？ 为什么只有我一个人？
- My!
- For what? Why was I alone?
他为什么缺席？
我为什么被捕？
Why was he absent?
Why was I arrested?
为什么我被推定死亡？
Why was I presumed dead?
我不知道。
I don't know.
我想象他不再
给你写情书，
I imagine he no longer
writes you love letters,
但你会很容易
识别你的笔迹。
but you will easily
recognize your handwriting.
然后。
Then.
瞧，梅赛德斯。
Look, Mercédès.
这是你老公写的
This is what your husband wrote
20年前到维尔福。
to Villefort 20 years ago.
我一定要报仇
梅赛德斯。必须如此。
I must take revenge,
Mercédès. It has to be.
所以，复仇吧，爱德蒙。
So take revenge, Edmond.
但关于罪魁祸首。
But about the culprits.
向背叛的费尔南多报仇
你，为我报仇，但饶过艾伯特吧。
Take revenge on Fernand who betrayed
you, take revenge on me, but spare Albert.
如果你知道所有的祈祷...
If you knew all the prayers...
如果你知道一切
我流下的泪水...
If you knew all
the tears I shed...
你是否失去了你的
父亲孤独吗？
Did you lose your
father in solitude?
你看到你的人了吗
爱在你的情敌怀里？
Did you see the person you
loved in the arms of your rival?
- 你看到这一切了吗？
- 不。
- Did you see all this?
- No.
是的。
Yes.
但我看到了我的那个人
从未停止过爱
But I see the man I
never stopped loving
准备成为杀害我儿子的凶手
ready to become my son's killer.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
你想让你的孩子活下去吗？
Do you want your child to live?
他会活下去。
He will live.
谢谢。
Thanks.
谢谢你，埃德蒙。
Thank you, Edmond.
我会再次找到你。
I will find you again.
我怎么一直梦想着
你，我一直多么爱你。
How I always dreamed of
you, how I always loved you.
我们必须说再见了。
We must say goodbye.
再见？
Goodbye?
如果我放弃伸张正义
交到我自己手里，
If I give up taking justice
into my own hands,
我放弃了让我活下去的东西。
I give up what keeps me alive.
决斗将进行
明天的地方。
The duel will take
place tomorrow.
再见，梅塞德斯。
Goodbye, Mercédès.
阿尔贝·德·马尔塞夫爵士，
Sir Albert de Morcerf,
公开挑衅
基督山伯爵。
publicly provoked the
Count of Monte Cristo.
决斗将于
20步，听我指挥。
The duel will take place at
20 paces, at my command.
优先考虑那些被冒犯的人。
Priority to those offended.
就位。
In position.
来吧，先生们。
Come on, gentlemen.
火！
Fire!
我想我看到了一丝
你眼中的失望。
I think I see a gleam of
disappointment in your eyes.
我永远不会原谅
你夺走了他的生命
I will never forgive
you for taking his life
并掏出我的心。
and for ripping out my heart.
所以我爱他。
So I loved him.
如果我爱他怎么办？
What if I loved him?
一切都让我讨厌他
但我们知道我们为什么相爱吗？
Everything made me hate him,
but do we know why we fell in love?
无论我们如何努力
互相讲道理，已经太晚了。
No matter how much we try to
reason with each other, it's too late.
我们失去了平衡。
We lost our balance.
没有机会了
There is no more chance
但与其听到这个
声音，我听到的是你的声音。
But instead of hearing this
voice, It's yours that I heard.
我会造成
他的不幸和我的不幸！
I would have caused
his misfortune and mine!
我要做什么
这份爱我没有给过你吗？
What am I going to do with
this love I didn't give you?
那些话里
我没告诉你吗？
Of those words
I didn't tell you?
你告诉他了。
You told him.
他听了他们的意见。
And he listened to them.
阿尔伯特...
Albert...
数数！
Count!
现在就逃吧。
Run away now.
逃跑，不让
任何人都会偷走你的幸福。
Run away and don't let
anyone steal your happiness.
埃德蒙！
Edmond!
艾德蒙，展现你自己吧！
Edmond, show yourself!
我在等你。
I was waiting for you.
终于露出了他的真面目。
Finally shows his true face.
我试图找到你的。
I tried to find yours.
知道他是谁。
Know who he was.
然后我就跟着
按照他的脚步。
Then I followed
in his footsteps.
我到处都去过
你去过。
I've been everywhere
you've been.
我遇见了他们所有人：
I met them all:
你的朋友，你的兄弟
武器，你的敌人，每个人......
your friends, your brothers in
arms, your enemies, everyone...
谁没被骗过？
Who hasn't cheated?
你对谁保持忠诚？
To whom did you remain loyal?
无处不在的你
露出了你的真面目。
Everywhere, you
showed your true face.
我输了
I lost
对人的信心，
faith in man,
你背叛我的那一天。
the day you betrayed me.
我应该自杀的。
I should have killed myself.
永远不会太晚。
It's never too late.
起床。
Get up.
看着我。
Look at me.
看着我！
Look at me!
他喘着粗气。
He pants.
- 杀了我。
- Kill me.
我们总是发现
死者的伟大。
We always find
greatness in the dead.
我们最终原谅了他们。
We ended up forgiving them.
我不想被原谅。
I don't want to be forgiven.
梅赛德斯我来了
向你说再见
Mercédès, I came
to say goodbye to you
生命分离的地方
我们彼此，
where life separated
us from each other,
21年前的今天。
21 years ago today.
很多东西都坏了
从那时起，在我和我周围，
So many things have broken
in me and around me since then,
我认识的那个人
不再存在。
that the man I knew
no longer exists.
我答应过
爱你直到我死
I promised to
love you until I die
而又过了很长一段时间，
and still a long time later,
我会永远爱你，
and I will always love you,
但它已经不再是我的了
给你带来幸福的力量。
but it is no longer in my
power to bring you happiness.
我只能给你安慰。
I can only offer you comfort.
你的孩子会很高兴。
Your child will be happy.
艾伯特和海黛将活着
我们无法经历的故事。
Albert and Haydée will live
the story we couldn't experience.
为我们的孩子带来幸福
Happiness for our children
这将使我们生存下去并且
尝到爱情的甜蜜。
that will survive us and
taste the sweetness of love.
当我写信给你时，我还活着
我和你在一起的最后时刻。
As I write to you, I am living
my last moments with you.
之后的一切
将只是回忆。
Everything afterward
will be just memories.
我会带他们
和我一起去海边，
I will take them
with me to the sea,
地球上唯一的地方
一切都在地平线上
the only place on earth
where everything is horizon
以及哪里有
没有人类留下的痕迹。
and where there are
no traces left by men.
生活并快乐。
Live and be happy.
永远不要忘记，
Never forget,
直到天意降临的那一天
或许让我们再次相聚，
until the day when providence
perhaps brings us together again,
人类所有的智慧
就在这两个词里：
that all human wisdom
is in these two words:
等待
wait for
和希望。
and hope.
埃德蒙·唐泰斯,
Edmond Dantes,
基督山伯爵。
the Count of Monte Cristo.